<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 372.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 113-499</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported original measure</name>
              <date>2014-06-27T16:31:43Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2014-06-28T04:47:03Z</createDate>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 372.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-499, by Ms. Granger.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-499</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/499</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-499, by Ms. Granger.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
          <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-499</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/499</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <committeeReportOfAnOriginalMeasure>1</committeeReportOfAnOriginalMeasure>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2014-06-27</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Ms. KAY GRANGER:H.R. 5013.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The principal constitutional authority for this legislationis clause 7 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution ofthe United States (the appropriation power), which states:``No Money shall be drawn from the Treasury, but inConsequence of Appropriations made by Law . . . .'' Inaddition, clause 1 of section 8 of article I of theConstitution (the spending power) provides: ``The Congressshall have the Power . . . to pay the Debts and provide forthe common Defence and general Welfare of the United States.. . .'' Together, these specific constitutional provisionsestablish the congressional power of the purse, grantingCongress the authority to appropriate funds, to determinetheir purpose, amount, and period of availability, and to setforth terms and conditions governing their use.[Page H5823]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>5013</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015 - Makes FY2015 appropriations for the Department of State for:</p> <ul> <li>administration of foreign affairs and diplomatic and consular programs;</li> <li>the Capital Investment Fund;</li> <li>the Office of Inspector General;</li> <li>educational and cultural exchange programs;</li> <li>representation allowances;</li> <li>protection of foreign missions and officials;</li> <li>U.S. embassy security, construction, and maintenance;</li> <li>emergencies in the diplomatic and consular service;</li> <li>the repatriation loans program account;</li> <li>the American Institute in Taiwan;</li> <li>the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund;</li> <li>international organizations, peacekeeping, and commissions;</li> <li>the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico;</li> <li>salaries and expenses;</li> <li>plan preparation and construction of authorized projects;</li> <li>the International Joint Commission, the International Boundary Commission, United States and Canada, and the Border Environment Cooperation Commission;</li> <li>international fisheries commissions;</li> <li>international broadcasting operations and capital improvements;</li> <li>the Asia Foundation;</li> <li>the United States Institute for Peace;</li> <li>the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund;</li> <li>the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated;</li> <li>the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program;</li> <li>the National Endowment for Democracy;</li> <li>the Commission for Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad;</li> <li>the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom;</li> <li>the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe;</li> <li>the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China; and</li> <li>the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission.</li> </ul> <p>Makes FY2015 appropriations for:</p> <ul> <li>operating expenses of the U. S. Agency for International Development (USAID), the capital investment fund, and the Office of Inspector General;</li> <li>expenses of the President in carrying out certain programs under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961,</li> <li>global health and child survival;</li> <li>specified development assistance;</li> <li>international disaster assistance;</li> <li>transition initiatives;</li> <li>development credit authority;</li> <li>the Economic Support Fund;</li> <li>promotion of democracy;</li> <li>migration and refugee assistance;</li> <li>the Peace Corps;</li> <li>the Millennium Challenge Corporation;</li> <li>the Inter-American Foundation;</li> <li>the African Development Foundation;</li> <li>the Department of the Treasury for international affairs technical assistance activities;</li> <li>international narcotics control and law enforcement;</li> <li>nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, and demining;</li> <li>international peacekeeping operations;</li> <li>international military education and training;</li> <li>foreign military financing grants;</li> <li>international organizations and programs;</li> <li>the Global Environment Facility;</li> <li>the International Development Association;</li> <li>the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development;</li> <li>the Global Agriculture and Food Security Program;</li> <li>the Inter-American Development Bank;</li> <li>the Asian Development Bank;</li> <li>the Asian Development Fund;</li> <li>the African Development Bank;</li> <li>the African Development Fund;</li> <li>the International Fund for Agricultural Development;</li> <li> the Export-Import Bank of the United States, including the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC); and</li> <li>the Trade and Development Agency. </li> </ul> <p>Sets forth limitations on callable capital subscriptions with respect to:</p> <ul> <li>the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development;</li> <li>the Inter-American Development Bank;</li> <li>the Asian Development Bank; and</li> <li>the African Development Bank. </li></ul> <p>Sets forth certain limits and prohibitions on the use of appropriations for specified activities.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-06-27T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-07-01T18:05:27Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015 - <b>Title I: Department of State and Related Agency -</b> Makes FY2015 appropriations for the Department of State (Department) for: </p> <ul> <li>administration of foreign affairs and diplomatic and consular programs; </li> <li>the Capital Investment Fund; </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>educational and cultural exchange programs; </li> <li>representation allowances; </li> <li>protection of foreign missions and officials; </li> <li>U.S. embassy security, construction, and maintenance; </li> <li>emergencies in the diplomatic and consular service; </li> <li>the repatriation loans program account; </li> <li>the American Institute in Taiwan; </li> <li>the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund; </li> <li>international organizations, peacekeeping, and commissions; </li> <li>the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico; </li> <li>salaries and expenses; </li> <li>plan preparation and construction of authorized projects; </li> <li>the International Joint Commission, the International Boundary Commission, United States and Canada, and the Border Environment Cooperation Commission; </li> <li>international fisheries commissions; </li> <li>international broadcasting operations and capital improvements; </li> <li>the Asia Foundation; </li> <li>the United States Institute for Peace; </li> <li>the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund; </li> <li>the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated; </li> <li>the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program; </li> <li>the National Endowment for Democracy; </li> <li>the Commission for Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad; </li> <li>the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom; </li> <li>the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe; </li> <li>the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China; and </li> <LI>the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission. </LI> </ul> <p><b>Title II: United States Agency for International Development </b>- Makes FY2015 appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li>operating expenses of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), </li> <li>the capital investment fund, and </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p><b>Title III: Bilateral Economic Assistance -</b> Makes FY2015 appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li>expenses of the President in carrying out certain programs under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, </li> <li>global health and child survival, </li> <li>specified development assistance, </li> <li>international disaster assistance, </li> <li>transition initiatives, </li> <li>development credit authority, </li> <li>the Economic Support Fund, </li> <li>promotion of democracy, </li> <li>migration and refugee assistance, </li> <li>the Peace Corps, </li> <li>the Millennium Challenge Corporation, </li> <li>the Inter-American Foundation, </li> <li>the African Development Foundation, and </li> <li>the Department of the Treasury for international affairs technical assistance activities. </li> </ul> <p><b>Title IV: International Security Assistance </b>- Makes FY2015 appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li>international narcotics control and law enforcement; </li> <li>nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, and demining; </li> <li>international peacekeeping operations; </li> <li>international military education and training; and </li> <li>foreign military financing grants. </li> </ul> <p><b>Title V: Multilateral Assistance -</b> Makes FY2015 appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li>international organizations and programs; </li> <li>the Global Environment Facility; </li> <li>the International Development Association; </li> <li>the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development; </li> <li>the Global Agriculture and Food Security Program; </li> <li>the Inter-American Development Bank; </li> <li>the Asian Development Bank; </li> <li>the Asian Development Fund; </li> <li>the African Development Bank; </li> <li>the African Development Fund; </li> <li>the International Fund for Agricultural Development; </li> <li>the Export-Import Bank of the United States, including the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC); and </li> <li>the Trade and Development Agency. </li> </ul> <p>Sets forth limitations on callable capital subscriptions with respect to: </p> <ul> <li>the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, </li> <li>the Inter-American Development Bank, </li> <li>the Asian Development Bank, and </li> <li>the African Development Bank. </li> </ul> <p><b>Title VI: Export and Investment Assistance -</b> Makes FY2015 appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li>the Export-Import Bank of the United States, including the Office of Inspector General and administrative expenses; </li> <li>OPIC; and </li> <li>the Trade and Development Agency. </li> </ul> <p><b>Title VII: General Provisions</b> - Sets forth certain limits and prohibitions on the use of appropriations for specified activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 7002) Requires any federal department or agency that has funds made available to it under this Act to provide Congress with a quarterly accounting of the cumulative balances of any unobligated funds received during FY2015 or in any previous fiscal year. </p> <p>(Sec. 7003) Limits the use of funds under title I of this Act for any consulting service through procurement contracts to those contracts available for public inspection. </p> <p>(Sec. 7004) Sets forth restrictions on office space for federal employees with respect to U.S. diplomatic facility construction, with an exception for Marine Corps use. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of certain funding sources for site acquisition and mitigation, planning, design or construction of the New London Embassy, United Kingdom.</p> <p> Declares that certain embassy security, construction, and maintenance appropriations may be obligated for the relocation of the U.S. Embassy to the Holy See only if the U.S. Ambassador to the Holy See and embassy staff will retain their independence from other U.S. missions in Rome, and any relocation of the chancery will not increase annual operating costs or result in a reduction in staff, and will enhance the Embassy's overall security. </p> <p> (Sec. 7005) States that costs incurred by an agency or department funded under title I of this Act resulting from personnel actions taken in response to funding reductions included in this Act shall be absorbed within such agency's or department's budgetary resources. </p> <p>(Sec. 7006) Prohibits first-class travel by employees of agencies funded under this Act in contravention of specified federal regulations.</p> <p>(Sec. 7007) Prohibits the use of funds under titles III through VI of this Act for direct assistance or reparations to Cuba, North Korea, Iran, or Syria. </p> <p>(Sec. 7008) Prohibits the use of funds under titles III through VI this Act for assistance to any country whose elected head of government is deposed by military or military-supported coup or decree. Permits resuming assistance if a democratic government is subsequently elected to office. </p> <p>(Sec. 7009) Limits certain agency, Department, and Broadcasting Board of Governors transfer authority. </p> <p>(Sec. 7010) Directs the Secretary of State to report to Congress quarterly on fund use for foreign military financing, international military education and training, peacekeeping operations, and the Pakistan Counterinsurgency Capability Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 7011) Prohibits, with specified exceptions, appropriations under this Act from remaining available for obligation after the expiration of the current fiscal year unless expressly provided for. </p> <p>(Sec. 7012) Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being used for assistance to any country in default in excess of a year on payments on a U.S. loan unless the President determines that such assistance is in the U.S. national interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 7013) Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being used for assistance under a new bilateral agreement unless such assistance is exempt from taxation, or reimbursed, by the foreign government. </p> <p>(Sec. 7014) Authorizes specifically designated appropriations under titles II through VI of this Act to be reprogrammed for other programs within the same account subject to the appropriate congressional committees' regular notification procedures. </p> <p>Extends the availability of program-specific appropriations for one fiscal year if the Secretary or USAID reports to Congress that program termination or changed circumstances makes it unlikely that such appropriations can be obligated during the original period of availability. </p> <p>States that ceilings and specifically designated funding levels under this Act shall not be applicable to funds or authorities appropriated or otherwise made available by any subsequent Act unless such Act specifically so directs. </p> <p>(Sec. 7015) Prohibits funds that remain available for FY2015 obligation under titles I and II of this Act or in prior appropriations Acts from being made available for specified reprogramming purposes unless the appropriate congressional committees are notified 15 days in advance of such programming. </p> <p>States that the requirements of this section or any similar provision may be waived if failure to do so would pose a substantial risk to human health or welfare. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds under titles III through VI of this Act for Afghanistan, Burma, Cambodia, Cuba, Ethiopia, Haiti, Iran, Iraq, Lebanon, Libya, Pakistan, the Russian Federation, Serbia, Somalia, Sri Lanka, South Sudan, Sudan, Syria,Uzbekistan, Yemen, and Zimbabwe except through the regular notification procedures of the appropriate congressional committees. </p> <p>(Sec. 7016) Requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to notify Congress before: (1) providing certain excess defense articles under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, or (2) issuing a letter of offer to sell certain defense articles under the Arms Export Control Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 7017) States that funds appropriated under titles III through VI of this Act or in prior appropriations Acts for the Department, foreign operations, export financing, and related programs that are returned or not made available for international organizations and programs shall remain available for obligation until September 30, 2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 7018) Prohibits certain funds under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 from being: (1) used to pay for abortions, involuntary sterilizations, or related biomedical research as a method of family planning; or (2) obligated or expended for any country or organization if such funds' use would violate specified provisions related to abortions and involuntary sterilizations. </p> <p>(Sec. 7019) Allocates funds for specified accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 7020) Prohibits the obligation of certain funds to pay for alcoholic beverages or entertainment expenses for recreational activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 7021) Prohibits the provision of funds under titles III through VI of this Act to any foreign government that provides lethal military equipment to a country that supports international terrorism unless the President reports to Congress that such assistance is in U.S. national interests. </p> <p>Prohibits bilateral assistance from being made to a government that: (1) grants sanctuary from prosecution to any individual or group which has committed an act of international terrorism, (2) otherwise supports international terrorism, or (3) is controlled by a terrorist organization. Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition for humanitarian or national security purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 7022) Extends, with an exception, certain authorities necessary to expend Department and foreign assistance funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 7024) States that, unless expressly provided to the contrary, provisions authorizing or making appropriations for the Department, foreign operations, and related programs shall not be construed to prohibit activities authorized by the Peace Corps Act, the Inter-American Foundation Act, or the African Development Foundation Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 7025) Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act and funds available to the Export-Import Bank and OPIC from being used for production of any export commodity by a foreign country if the commodity is likely to be in surplus on world markets and will cause substantial injury to U.S. producers of a similar or competing commodity (with exceptions for benefits to U.S. producers). </p> <p>(Sec. 7026) Directs USAID to require countries that receive foreign assistance which results in the generation of local currencies to deposit such currencies in a separate account to be used to finance foreign assistance activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 7027) States that: (1) restrictions on assistance for a country shall not be construed to restrict specified assistance for nongovernmental organizations from certain funds under this Act, and (2) nothing in this section shall be construed to alter existing prohibitions against abortion or involuntary sterilizations in this or any other Act. </p> <p>States that: (1) during FY2015 restrictions contained in this or any other Act with respect to assistance for a country shall not be construed to restrict assistance under the Food for Peace Act, and (2) this section shall not apply to assistance restrictions regarding support of international terrorism and human rights violations. </p> <p>(Sec. 7028) Sets forth the conditions under which funds available under this Act for USAID may be provided for limited competitions through local entities. </p> <p>(Sec. 7029) States that none of the funds under title V of this Act should be paid to any international financial institution unless the Secretary of the Treasury certifies to Congress that such institution requires independent evaluations of each project, program loan or grant, or significant non-lending activity. </p> <p>Prohibits payments under title V of this Act to any international financial institution while the U.S. executive director to the institution is compensated at a rate in excess of that for Level IV of the Executive Schedule, or any alternate U.S. director is compensated at a rate in excess of that for Level V of such Schedule. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct: </p> <ul> <li>the U.S. Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to oppose assistance to a Heavily Indebted Poor Country that imposes budget caps or restraints that do not allow the maintenance of or an increase in governmental spending on health care or education, and </li> <li>the U.S. executive directors at international financial entities to oppose assistance that requires user fees or service charges on poor people for primary education or primary health care. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7030) Authorizes nongovernmental organizations which are USAID grantees or contractors to place funds made available to them under title III of this Act in interest bearing accounts in order to enhance their participation in debt-for-development and debt-for-nature exchanges. </p> <p>(Sec. 7031) Sets forth requirements for direct government-to government assistance. </p> <p>(Sec. 7032) Makes funds available to support freedom of religion, including in the Middle East and North Africa. </p> <p>(Sec. 7033) Conditions the use of funds appropriated by this Act to make any pledge for future year funding for any multilateral or bilateral program funded in titles III through VI of this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 7034) Makes funds under titles III through VI of this Act available for: (1) war victims, (2) displaced children, (3) displaced Burmese, and (4) victims of trafficking in persons and to combat such trafficking. </p> <p>Expands authorities under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for civilian police assistance for a regional, district, municipal, or other sub-national entity emerging from instability. </p> <p>Makes specified funds available for: </p> <ul> <li>the World Food Program; </li> <li>programs to disarm, demobilize, and reintegrate into civilian society former members of foreign terrorist organizations; </li> <li>the Partner Vetting System pilot program; </li> <li>the program for research and training on Eastern Europe and the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union; and </li> <li>contingencies. </li> </ul> <p> Urges the Secretary to withhold funds under title III of this Act for the central government of any country that is not taking appropriate steps to comply with the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abductions. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to transfer unobligated expired FY2015 diplomatic and consular program balances to the protection of foreign missions account, except for funds designated for overseas contingency operations and the war on terror. </p> <p>Extends: </p> <ul> <li>funding authority for recruitment, relocation, and retention bonuses to Foreign Service members, other than chiefs of mission and ambassadors at large, who are on official duty in Iraq, Afghanistan, or Pakistan; </li> <li>specified authorities on reemployment requirements for certain annuitants reemployed in Iraq, Pakistan, and Afghanistan; </li> <li>authority of USAID's Office of Inspector General to contract with U.S. citizens for personal services if the Office's personnel resources are otherwise insufficient; </li> <li>refugee set-asides for nationals of the former Soviet Union, Estonia, Latvia, or Lithuania who are current, active members of the Ukrainian Catholic Church or the Ukrainian Orthodox Church; and </li> <li>the period of eligibility for status adjustment from a parolee who was denied refugee status to a lawfully admitted permanent resident for certain aliens from the former Soviet Union, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Vietnam, Laos, or Cambodia. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7035) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Arab League boycott of Israel (reinstated in 1997), and the secondary boycott of American firms that have commercial ties with Israel, is an impediment to regional peace and to U.S. investment and trade in the Middle East and North Africa and should be terminated; and (2) the President should report annually to Congress on steps taken to encourage Arab League states to normalize their relations with Israel to end the boycott. </p> <p>(Sec. 7036) Prohibits, with a national security interest waiver, the use of funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being used to support a Palestinian state unless the Secretary certifies to Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>the Palestinian governing entity has demonstrated a commitment to peaceful coexistence with Israel and is taking measures to counter terrorism, and </li> <li>the Palestinian Authority (PA) or a new governing entity is working to establish a lasting peace in the Middle East. Exempts from such restriction assistance to help reform the PA and affiliated institutions or a governing entity meet such assistance requirements. </li> </ul> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that the governing entity should enact a constitution assuring the rule of law, an independent judiciary, and respect for human rights, and should enact other laws assuring accountable governance. </p> <p>(Sec. 7037) Prohibits the obligation of funds appropriated under titles II through VI of this Act, except for acquisition of additional space for the Consulate General, to create in Jerusalem a new U.S. agency office for the purpose of conducting official U.S. business with the PA over Gaza and Jericho (or any successor Palestinian governing entity) provided for in the Israel-Palestine Liberation Organization Declaration of Principles. </p> <p>(Sec. 7038) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to provide equipment, technical support, consulting services, or any other assistance to the Palestinian Broadcasting Corporation. </p> <p>(Sec. 7039) Directs the Secretary, for FY2015, to certify to Congress prior to the initial obligation of funds for the bilateral West Bank and Gaza program that the Government Accountability Office (GAO) will have access to necessary financial information to evaluate the uses of U.S. assistance. Requires USAID audits at least once a year to ensure compliance with this section.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, before obligating economic support funds under this Act for the West Bank and Gaza, to take steps to ensure that such assistance is not provided to or through any individual or entity that advocates or engages in terrorist activity. </p> <p>Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being used to honor individuals who commit, or have committed, acts of terrorism. Requires and obligates funds for program audits. </p> <p>(Sec. 7040) Prohibits specified assistance to the PA unless the President certifies to Congress that it is in the U.S. national security interest. States that any such waiver shall: (1) not be for more than six months at a time, and (2) not apply beyond 12 months after enactment of this Act. Requires a report to Congress when such waiver is exercised. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of appropriations under titles III through VI of this Act for salaries of PA personnel in Gaza or for assistance to Hamas or any Hamas-controlled or power-sharing government unless the President certifies to Congress that it has accepted Israel's right to exist and is adhering to previous agreements with the United States, Israel, and the international community. </p> <p>Prohibits the obligation of funds under titles III through VI of this Act for the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO). </p> <p>(Sec. 7041) Makes funds under this Act available for the government of Egypt only if the Secretary certifies to Congress that such government is: (1) sustaining the strategic relationship with the United States, and (2) meeting its obligations under the 1979 Egypt-Israel Peace Treaty. </p> <p>Makes available specified: </p> <ul> <li>Economic Support Fund amounts for Egypt, including amounts for education and economic growth programs; </li> <li>foreign military financing funds to Egypt until September 30, 2016; and </li> <li>economic and military funds under this Act if Egypt has held parliamentary elections, and is taking steps to govern democratically. </li> </ul> <p>Makes funds available to Egypt for counterterrorism, border security, nonproliferation programs, and development activities in the Sinai. </p> <p>States that it is U.S. policy to prevent Iran from achieving the capability to produce nuclear weapons. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of specified funds by the Export-Import Bank of the United States to provide new financing to any person subject to sanctions under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996. </p> <p>States that funds under this Act for Iraq should be made available to Iraq to promote internal regional stability, including in Kurdistan to address requirements arising from regional conflict.</p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for construction or other improvements to U.S. facilities in Iraq on property for which no land-use agreement has been entered into by the governments of the United States and Iraq unless necessary to protect U.S. government facilities or U.S. personnel. </p> <p>Makes specified funds available to Jordan for: (1) foreign military financing, (2) economic support, and (3) costs related to regional instability.</p> <p>Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act for the Lebanese Armed Forces (LAF) if the LAF is controlled by a foreign terrorist organization. </p> <p>Makes foreign military financing funds available for Lebanon to professionalize the LAF, strengthen border security, and combat terrorism. </p> <p>Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act for the central government of Libya unless the Secretary reports to Congress that Libya is cooperating with U.S. efforts to bring to justice those responsible for the Benghazi attack in September 2012. Exempts from such limitation funding for protecting U.S. government personnel or facilities. </p> <p>Makes Economic Support Fund assistance available for: (1) loan guarantees for Tunisia and Jordan; and (2) enterprise funds for Egypt, Tunisia, and Jordan. </p> <p>States that funds appropriated under title III of this Act for Morocco shall also be available for any region or territory administered by Morocco, including the Western Sahara.</p> <p>Makes specified funds available for Syria to: </p> <ul> <li> establish representative and accountable governance; </li> <li>develop democratic political processes; </li> <li>further the Syrian opposition' s legitimacy through cross-border programs; </li> <li>develop civil society and an independent media; </li> <li>promote economic development; </li> <li>investigate and prosecute human rights violations in Syria, including through transitional justice programs and support for nongovernmental organizations; and </li> <li>counter extremist ideologies. </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary, before any obligation of funds under this Act for Syria, to ensure that mechanisms are in place for the adequate monitoring and control of assistance inside Syria. </p> <p>Requires congressional consultation before making funds under this section available for Syria. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary, before any obligation of Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act for the Palestinian Authority (PA), to report to Congress that the purpose of such assistance is to: </p> <ul> <li>advance Middle East peace, </li> <li>improve regional security, </li> <li>continue support for accountable government institutions, </li> <li>promote a private sector economy, or </li> <li>address urgent humanitarian needs. </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the availability of Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act for the PA if the Palestinians: </p> <ul> <li>obtain the same standing as a United Nations (U.N.) member state or full membership in the U.N. or any specialized U.N. agency outside an agreement negotiated between Israel and the Palestinians; or </li> <li>initiate an International Criminal Court (ICC) investigation, or actively support such an investigation, that subjects Israeli nationals to an investigation for alleged crimes against Palestinians. </li> </ul> <p>Reduces Economic Support Fund assistance for the PA by the amount expended by the PA as payments for acts of terrorism by individuals who are imprisoned after being fairly tried and convicted for acts of terrorism and by individuals who died committing acts of terrorism during the previous calendar year. </p> <p>Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act to the Armed Forces of Yemen if they are controlled by a foreign terrorist organization. </p> <p>(Sec. 7042) Makes funds under this Act for the Central African Republic available for reconciliation and peace building programs, including for programs to prevent crimes against humanity. </p> <p>Urges that specified funds should be made available for the trans-Sahara counterterrorism partnership program and the partnership for regional East Africa counterterrorism program. </p> <p>Makes funds under this Act available for programs in areas affected by the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) consistent with the goals of the Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act. </p> <p>Urges that funds under this Act for Liberia, Sierra Leone, Nigeria, Cote d'Ivoire, Senegal, Ghana, and the countries participating in the Congo Basin Forest Partnership be made available to promote transparency regarding the extraction of timber, oil, gas, cacao, and other natural resources. </p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for: (1) the government of Sudan, and (2) the cost of modifying loans and loan guarantees held by the government of Sudan.</p> <p>Exempts from such restrictions: </p> <ul> <li>humanitarian assistance;</li> <li>assistance for the Darfur region, Southern Kordofan State, Blue Nile State, other marginalized areas and populations in Sudan, and Abyei; and</li> <li>assistance to support implementation of outstanding issues of the Comprehensive Peace Agreement or any other internationally recognized viable peace agreement in Sudan. </li> </ul> <p>Urges that funds under this Act for assistance for South Sudan should: </p> <ul> <li> respond to humanitarian needs, deliver basic services, and mitigate conflict; </li> <li>support programs that address food insecurity, maintain educational opportunities, and enhance local governance; </li> <li>advance democratic principles; </li> <li>support transparency and accountability, including in the oil and gas sector; and </li> <li>support the professionalization of security forces. </li> </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct U.S. executive directors to international financial institutions to vote against any loan extensions to the government of Zimbabwe, except to meet basic human needs or to promote democracy, unless the Secretary reports to Congress that Zimbabwe has restored the rule of law. </p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act from being made to the government of Zimbabwe, except for health and education, unless the rule of law has been reestablished. </p> <p>(Sec. 7043) Authorizes Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act to Burma, except that such funds shall not be made available to any successor of the State Peace and Development Council controlled by former Council members who promote its repressive policies.</p> <p>States that funds under title III of this Act for Burma: </p> <ul> <li>may not be made available for budget support for the government; </li> <li>shall be provided to strengthen civil society organizations; </li> <li>shall be made available for community-based organizations operating in Thailand to provide food, medical, and other humanitarian assistance to internally displaced persons in eastern Burma; and </li> <li>shall be made available for ethnic and religious reconciliation programs, and to address the Rohingya and Kachin crises.</li> </ul> <p>States that funds under this Act should be made available to the government of Burma only if it has implemented constitutional reforms providing for inclusive participation in presidential and parliamentary elections. </p> <p>Prohibits Economic Support Fund assistance from being made available for the government of North Korea. </p> <p>Prohibits: </p> <ul> <li>specified funds under this Act from being obligated or expended for export licenses of U.S. origin satellites (including commercial satellites and satellite components) to China without prior notice to Congress; </li> <li>the use of funds under this Act to finance any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement with the People's Liberation Army or any affiliated entity; and </li> <li>specified funds under this Act from being made available for the government of China, except for disease prevention and treatment programs.</li> </ul> <p> Urges the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct U.S. executive directors of international financial institutions to support projects in Tibet if such projects do not provide incentives for the migration and settlement of non-Tibetans into Tibet or facilitate the transfer of ownership of Tibetan land and natural resources to non-Tibetans. </p> <p>Makes Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act available to nongovernmental organizations to preserve cultural traditions and promote sustainable development and environmental conservation in Tibetan communities in the Tibetan Autonomous Region and in other Tibetan communities in China. </p> <p>Makes Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act available for remediation of dioxin contaminated areas in Vietnam. </p> <p>(Sec. 7044) Prohibits the availability of funds under titles I and II of this Act for construction and renovation of U.S. government facilities in Afghanistan to accommodate federal employee positions or to expand aviation facilities or assets above those notified by the Department and USAID or contractors in addition to those in place on the date of enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Exempts from such restriction funds that are necessary to protect such facilities or the security and welfare of U.S. personnel. </p> <p>Withholds specified assistance from Afghanistan until the Secretary submits a required report (which shall be updated every six months until September 30, 2016) to Congress regarding Department and USAID transition and security plans. </p> <p>States that specified funds under this Act for Afghanistan: </p> <ul> <li>may not be used to initiate any new program or activity that would not have adequate oversight or involves any individual or organization involved in corrupt practices;</li> <li>shall only be made for programs that the government of Afghanistan or another Afghan entity is capable of sustaining; </li> <li>may be made for independent election bodies,</li> <li>shall be implemented in accordance with audit policies of the Department of State and USAID audit policies; and </li> </ul> <p>may be made for reconciliation programs and disarmament, demobilization, and reintegration activities for former combatants.</p> <p>Prohibits the obligation of specified funds under this Act for the government of Afghanistan unless the Secretary certifies to Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>the United States and Afghanistan have agreed to a Bilateral Security Agreement, </li> <li>Afghanistan is taking steps to protect the rights of Afghan women and girls, and </li> <li>Afghanistan is making credible efforts to reduce corruption and recover the stolen assets associated with Kabul Bank. </li> </ul> <p>Reduces assistance for the government of Afghanistan by $5 for every $1 that Afghanistan imposes in taxes or other fees on the transport of U.S. government property entering or leaving Afghanistan. </p> <p>Prohibits U.S. government use of funds under this Act to enter into a permanent basing rights agreement between the United States and Afghanistan.</p> <p>Withholds specified assistance for Pakistan until the Secretary certifies to Congress that Pakistan is: </p> <ul> <li>cooperating with the United States in counterterrorism efforts, </li> <li>not supporting terrorist activities against the United States or coalition forces in Afghanistan, </li> <li>preventing the proliferation of nuclear-related material and expertise, </li> <li>issuing visas in a timely manner for U.S. visitors engaged in counterterrorism and assistance efforts, </li> <li>dismantling improvised explosive device (IED) networks, and </li> <li>providing humanitarian organizations access to detainees and internally displaced persons. </li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the availability of specified military assistance to Pakistan only for counterterrorism and counterinsurgency capabilities in Pakistan. </p> <p>Withholds specified foreign military financing funds from Pakistan until the Secretary reports to Congress that Dr. Shakil Afridi has been released from prison and cleared of all charges relating to the assistance provided to the United States in locating Osama bin Laden. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to report to Congress detailing the costs and objectives associated with significant infrastructure projects supported by the United States in Pakistan. </p> <p>Prohibits, with humanitarian, demining, and disaster relief exceptions, the availability of specified funds to Sri Lanka unless the Secretary certifies to Congress that Sri Lanka is meeting specified conditions. </p> <p>States that, if the Secretary makes such certification, foreign military financing funds should be used to support the recruitment and training of Tamils into the Sri Lankan military, Tamil language training for Sinhalese military personnel, and human rights training for all military personnel. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct U.S. executive directors at international financial institutions to vote against any loan, agreement, or other financial support for Sri Lanka, except to meet basic human needs, unless the Secretary makes specified certifications. </p> <p>Makes specified economic support funds available for cross border stabilization and development programs between Afghanistan and Pakistan or between either country and the Central Asian countries. </p> <p>(Sec. 7045) Authorizes the use of funds under this Act for Columbia for a campaign against narcotics trafficking, illegal armed groups, and foreign terrorist organizations and to protect human health and welfare in emergency circumstances. </p> <p>Makes Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act available for Cuba to promote democracy and strengthen civil society. </p> <p>Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act for the government of Haiti until the Secretary certifies to Congress that Haiti: (1) has held free and fair parliamentary elections and a new Haitian Parliament is functioning, (2) is respecting the independence of the judiciary, and (3) is taking effective steps to combat corruption and improve governance. </p> <p>Makes Haiti eligible to purchase U.S. defense articles and services for its Coast Guard. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to submit a specified report to Congress regarding Honduras.</p> <p>Makes assistance available for Mexico and Central American countries to: (1) enhance border security, (2) combat human trafficking and smuggling, and (3) provide for the repatriation and reintegration of citizens from such countries. Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress a multi-country strategy for implementing such enhanced border security initiatives (which shall focus on the southern border of Mexico).</p> <p>Makes specified funds under this Act available for DNA forensic technology programs to combat human trafficking in Central America. </p> <p>Urges that specified funds under this Act be made available for labor and environmental capacity building activities relating to free trade agreements with countries of Central America, Colombia, Peru, and the Dominican Republic.</p> <p>(Sec. 7046) Prohibits the use of funds under titles III through VI of this Act to pay any assessments, arrearages, or dues of any U.N. member, or from certain funds under this Act for the costs for attendance of another country's delegation at international conferences held under the auspices of multilateral or international organizations. </p> <p>(Sec. 7047) Permits the President to provide up to a specified amount of commodities and services to the United Nations War Crimes Tribunal if doing so will contribute to a just resolution of charges regarding genocide or other violations of international law in the former Yugoslavia. </p> <p>(Sec. 7048) Withholds specified funds under titles I and V of this Act for contributions to any U.N. agency or the Organization of American States (OAS) if the Secretary reports to Congress that the agency or organization is not taking specified actions regarding whistle blower protection and financial and performance transparency. </p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to pay expenses for any U.S. delegation to any specialized U.N. agency, body, or commission that is presided over by a country that supports international terrorism. </p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) unless the Secretary reports to Congress that: (1) UNRHC participation is in the U.S. national interest, and (2) UNRHC is taking steps to remove Israel as a permanent agenda item.</p> <p>Prohibits specified funds under this Act from being made available as a contribution to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) until the Secretary reports to Congress that UNRWA is: </p> <ul> <li>inspecting its installations for any inappropriate use and addressing any staff or beneficiary violation of its policies, including policies on employee neutrality; </li> <li>ensuring that it is operating in compliance with the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; </li> <li>ensuring that the content of educational materials in UNRWA-administered schools and summer camps is consistent with the values of human rights, dignity, and tolerance and does not induce incitement; </li> <li>not engaging in operations with financial institutions or related entities in violation of relevant U.S. law, and is taking steps to improve financial transparency; and </li> <li>in compliance with the United Nations Board of Auditors' biennial audit requirements. </ul> <p>Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for the design, renovation, or construction of the U.N. Headquarters in New York. </p> <p>(Sec. 7049) Authorizes the use of specified funds under titles III and IV of this Act to enhance the effectiveness and accountability of civilian police authority through human rights training and through the promotion of civilian police roles that support democratic governance, including programs on conflict prevention, police-community relations, disaster assistance, and gender-based violence. </p> <p>(Sec. 7050) Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products, or to seek the reduction or removal by any foreign country of restrictions on the marketing of tobacco or tobacco products. </p> <p>(Sec. 7051) Prohibits the use of specified funds to send or otherwise pay for the attendance of more than 50 U.S.-stationed employees from a federal department or agency at any single conference outside the United States unless such attendance is important to the national interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 7052) Authorizes the transfer of certain aircraft including for the transportation of active and standby Civilian Response Corps personnel and equipment. </p> <p>Requires that the use of Department and USAID aircraft used primarily to transport personnel be coordinated under the authority of the appropriate Chief of Mission. </p> <p>(Sec. 7053) Withholds assistance from a foreign country in an amount equal to 110% of the total unpaid property tax and unpaid parking fines and penalties incurred April 1, 1997-September 30, 2014, and owed by the country to the District of Columbia or New York City. </p> <p>(Sec. 7054) Authorizes disposal on a grant basis in foreign countries of demining equipment used in support of the clearance of land mines and unexploded ordnance for humanitarian purposes. </p> <p>Restricts military assistance for cluster munitions. </p> <p>(Sec. 7055) Prohibits the use of funds for publicity or propaganda purposes within the United States that were not authorized before the enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Makes specified funds available for USAID assistance to private and voluntary organizations engaged in facilitating public discussion of hunger and other related issues. </p> <p>(Sec. 7056) Limits the amount of funds under title II of this Act that may be used for official USAID residence expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 7057) Allocates specified funds under title III of this Act for USAID to hire up to 175 persons per fiscal year on a limited appointment basis in the United States and abroad. Conditions such hirings upon an equivalent elimination of USAID nondirect-hire employees. Terminates such authority on September 30, 2016.</p> <p>Authorizes up to four-year extensions for limited-appointment Foreign Service personnel. </p> <p>Authorizes specified funds under title III of this Act for the costs of persons detailed to or employed by USAID to carry out natural or man-made disaster response programs. </p> <p>Authorizes specified funds under this Act to be used by USAID to employ up to 40 personal services contractors in the United States for new or expanded overseas programs until permanent personnel are hired. Limits to 15 the number of such contractors that may be assigned to any bureau or office. </p> <p>Continues USAID authority to appoint into the Senior Foreign Service and employ up to 10 individuals for programs in Afghanistan or Pakistan. </p> <p>(Sec. 7058) States that funds appropriated by titles III and IV of this Act for bilateral assistance for child survival activities or disease programs, including HIV/AIDS research, prevention and treatment activities, may be made available notwithstanding any other provision of law with specified exceptions. </p> <p>Authorizes the use of specified funds under this Act for family planning/reproductive health. </p> <p>Authorizes funds under title III of this Act to: (1) combat a pandemic virus if the President reports to Congress that the virus is severe and is spreading internationally, and (2) combat polio.</p> <p>Withholds specified funds from the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria until the Secretary reports to Congress that the Fund is implementing a policy of transparency and maintaining a policy to protect whistle blowers from retaliation. </p> <p>(Sec. 7059) Makes specified funds under this Act available for: (1) gender programs, (2) programs to increase political opportunities for women in countries where women and girls suffer severe forms of discrimination, and (3) a multi-year strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence in countries where it is common. </p> <p>Makes funds under this Act available to empower women as equal partners in conflict prevention, peace building, and reconstruction efforts. </p> <p>States that programs funded under titles III and IV of this Act to train foreign police and judicial and military personnel shall: (1) address prevention and response to gender-based violence and trafficking in persons, and (2) promote the integration of women into the police and other security forces of their countries. </p> <p>(Sec. 7060) Allocates specified funds for: </p> <ul> <li>basic and higher education, </li> <li>the development grants program, </li> <li>conservation programs, </li> <li>food security and agriculture development programs, </li> <li>microenterprise and microfinance development programs for the poor and women, </li> <li>activities to combat trafficking in persons, and </li> <li>water and sanitation supply projects.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7061) Prohibits funds under this Act from being obligated or expended to implement the Arms Trade Treaty until the Senate approves a resolution of ratification for the Treaty. </p> <p>(Sec. 7062) Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being provided to a nongovernmental organization or contractor which fails to provide documents, files, or records for USAID auditing requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 7063) Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for: (1) the United Nations Population Fund; and (2)population planning activities to any foreign nongovernmental organization that promotes or performs abortions, except in cases of rape or incest or when the mother's life would be endangered.</p> <p>(Sec. 7064) Prohibits appropriations for the Department, foreign operations, and related programs from being obligated for any country, including a state with a compact of free association with the United States, that concludes an agreement with the United States to receive by transfer or release individuals detained at Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, unless the Secretary notifies Congress of such agreement's terms prior to its implementation. </p> <p>(Sec. 7065) Obligates specified funds under this Act for assistance to eliminate inhumane conditions in foreign prisons and other detention facilities.</p> <p>(Sec. 7066) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to support or justify the use of torture, cruel, or inhumane treatment by any U.S. government official or contract employee. </p> <p>(Sec. 7067) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act (other than funds for narcotics control and law enforcement, refugee assistance, or antiterrorism activities) to assist the government of a country with which the United States has diplomatic relations and an extradition treaty and refuses to extradite to the United States any individual charged with a criminal offense for which the maximum penalty is life imprisonment without parole, or for killing a law enforcement officer. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to waive such restriction on a case-by-case basis if important to U.S. national interests. </p> <p>(Sec. 7068) Authorizes the commercial leasing of certain defense articles (instead of the government-to-government sale) to Israel, Egypt, North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) members, and major non-NATO allies if the President determines that there are compelling foreign policy or national security reasons. </p> <p>(Sec. 7069) Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for assistance to the government of the Russian Federation.</p> <p>Prohibits funds under this Act, subject to a U.S. national interest waiver, from being made available for a government of an Independent State of the former Soviet Union that directs any action in violation of the territorial integrity or national sovereignty of any other Independent State of the former Soviet Union. </p> <p>Authorizes Economic Support Fund assistance under this Act to specified countries pursuant to the Support for Eastern European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 and the FREEDOM Support Act. </p> <p>Makes specified funds under this Act available for enhanced programs to counter external, regional aggression and influence in Ukraine and other Independent States of the Former Soviet Union and Central and Eastern Europe. </p> <p>(Sec. 7070) Extends certain IMF transparency requirements to this Act. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the IMF to ensure that any loan will be repaid to the IMF before other private creditors, and (2) ensure that the IMF is implementing whistle blower best practices. </p> <p>(Sec. 7071) Prohibits the provision of funds under titles III through VI of this Act for: (1) any financial incentive to a business for purposes of inducing it to relocate outside the United States if it will reduce the number of U.S. employees, or (2) assistance for any program that contributes to the violation of internationally recognized workers rights in the recipient country. </p> <p>(Sec. 7072) Obligates funds for the Special Defense Acquisition Fund, to remain available for obligation until September 30, 2017.</p> <p>(Sec. 7073) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act, with a specified exception, to enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with, make a grant to, or provide a loan or loan guarantee to a corporation that was convicted of a federal felony within the preceding 24 months, or has unpaid federal taxes if the awarding agency has knowledge of the conviction or unpaid taxes. </p> <p>(Sec. 7074) Prohibits funds under titles III through VI of this Act from being made available for Enterprise Funds unless Congress is notified 15 days in advance. </p> <p>Directs the President to submit to Congress a plan for the distribution of the assets of an Enterprise Fund before any distribution resulting from liquidation, dissolution, or winding up of the Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 7075) States that if the President makes a determination not to comply with any provision of this Act on constitutional grounds, the head of the relevant federal agency shall notify Congress within five days regarding the basis for such determination and any resulting program and policy changes.</p> <p>(Sec. 7076) Requires each department, agency, or organization funded under titles I and II of this Act, and the Department of the Treasury and the independent agencies funded under title III of this Act to submit to Congress an operating plan for funds appropriated or otherwise available for obligation in FY2015.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress a spend plan for funds made available under titles III and IV of this Act for: </p> <ul> <li>Afghanistan, Colombia, Egypt, Iraq, Lebanon, Libya, Mexico, Pakistan, Yemen, and the West Bank and Gaza; </li> <li>democracy programs and sectors set forth in section 760 of this Act; and </li> <li>the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative, the Central American Regional Security Initiative, the Trans-Sahara Counterterrorism Partnership program, and the Partnership for Regional East Africa Counterterrorism program. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7077) Obligates specified funds under titles I and III of this Act for programs to promote Internet freedom globally. Prioritizes such funds for those countries whose governments restrict Internet freedom and that are important to U.S. national interests. </p> <p>(Sec. 7078) Directs the Secretary to rename the section of International Place, DC, which runs in front of the Embassy of China, as Liu Xiaobo Plaza.</p> <p>States that hereafter the Embassy's address shall be No. 1 Liu Xiaobo Plaza. </p> <p><b>Title VIII: Overseas Contingency Operations </b>- Appropriates additional funds to the Department for: (1) diplomatic and consular programs; (2) the Office of Inspector General; and (3) embassy security, construction, and maintenance.</p> <p>Appropriates additional funds to USAID for operating expenses.</p> <p>Appropriates additional bilateral assistance funds to the President for: (1) international disaster assistance, and (2) the Economic Support Fund. </p> <p>Appropriates additional bilateral assistance funds to the Department for migration and refugee assistance. </p> <p>Appropriates additional security assistance funds to the Department for: (1) international narcotics control and law enforcement; (2) nonproliferation, antiterrorism, and demining; and (3) peacekeeping operations. </p> <p>Appropriates additional funds to the President for the foreign military financing program. </p> <p>(Sec. 8001) States that: (1) funds appropriated in this title are in addition to amounts appropriated or otherwise made available in this Act for FY2015, and (2) such additional funds shall be available under the authorities and conditions applicable to such appropriations accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 8003) Authorizes the transfer of specified funds under this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 8004) States that each amount designated in this Act by Congress for overseas contingency operations/global war on terrorism pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 shall be available (or rescinded, if applicable) only if the President subsequently so designates all such amounts and transmits such designations to the Congress.</p> <p><b>Title IX: Additional General Provision </b>- (Sec. 9001) States that the amount by which the applicable allocation of new budget authority made by the House Committee on Appropriations pursuant to the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority is $0.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-06-27T16:31:43Z</updateDate>
          <name>Reported to House without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>79</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House without amendment</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-09-18T20:52:14Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-06-27</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Abortion</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Afghanistan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Africa</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>African Development Foundation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Agricultural trade</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Air quality</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Appropriations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Arab-Israeli relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Area studies and international education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Arms control and nonproliferation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Asia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aviation and airports</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Building construction</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Burma</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Canada</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Caribbean area</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Central African Republic</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Child safety and welfare</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>China</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Coal</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Colombia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional tributes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Corporate finance and management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Correctional facilities and imprisonment</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Crimes against children</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Crimes against women</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Cuba</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Cultural exchanges and relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Currency</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of State</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Treasury</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Detention of persons</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>District of Columbia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Economic development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Egypt</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Employment discrimination and employee rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Europe</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Export-Import Bank of the United States</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Family planning and birth control</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Food assistance and relief</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign loans and debt</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Gaza Strip</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Guatemala</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>HIV/AIDS</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Haiti</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historical and cultural resources</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Honduras</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Human rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Human trafficking</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Infectious and parasitic diseases</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Inter-American Foundation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>International exchange and broadcasting</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Internet and video services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Iran</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Iraq</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Israel</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Jordan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Latin America</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lebanon</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Libya</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Mexico</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Middle East</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military assistance, sales, and agreements</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military education and training</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military facilities and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Minority and disadvantaged businesses</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Morocco</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Multilateral development programs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>North Korea</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Pakistan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Palestinians</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Peace Corps</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Political movements and philosophies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Property rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Property tax</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Protection of officials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Reconstruction and stabilization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Refugees, asylum, displaced persons</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Religion</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Roads and highways</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Russia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sanctions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sex and reproductive health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Small business</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Smuggling and trafficking</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>South Sudan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sri Lanka</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sudan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Syria</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Taiwan</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Tax administration and collection, taxpayers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Terrorism</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Tibet</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Trade and Development Agency</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Trade restrictions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Travel and tourism</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. Institute of Peace</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. and foreign investments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Vietnam</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Visas and passports</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water quality</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>West Bank</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Women in business</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Women's rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>World health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Yemen</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Zimbabwe</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <title>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:14:42Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>TX</state>
        <firstName>KAY</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>G000377</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Granger, Kay [R-TX-12]</fullName>
        <lastName>GRANGER</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>12</district>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000377</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8168</gpoId>
          <lisID>1487</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number />
        <calendar>U00372</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>83</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 113-235.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1372</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, Fiscal Year 2014</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-12-10</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-484.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>2499</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-06-19</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 435.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R.83, which became Public Law 113-235 on 12/16/2014.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/83</url>
            <name>H.R.83</name>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

