<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Banking and financial institutions regulation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal Reserve System</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Financial services and investments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign and international banking</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Inflation and prices</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Small business</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Travel and tourism</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Scott</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Garrett, Scott [R-NJ-5]</fullName>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000548</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1737</lisID>
          <gpoId>8047</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Garrett</lastName>
        <district>5</district>
        <bioguideId>G000548</bioguideId>
        <byRequestType />
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <createDate>2014-01-28T07:02:07Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:10:20Z</updateDate>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <notes />
    <committeeReports />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. GARRETT:H.R. 3928.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8, Clause 3 (To regulate commerce withforeign nations, and among the several states, and with theIndian tribes); Article I, Section 8, Clause 5 (To coinmoney, regulate the value thereof, and of foreign coin, andfix the standard of weights and measures); Article I, Section8, Clause 6 (To provide for the punishment of counterfeitingthe securities and current coin of the United States); andArticle I, Section 8, Clause 18 (To make all laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into execution theforegoing powers, and all other powers vested by thisConstitution in the government of the United States, or inany department thereof).[Page H1431]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <introducedDate>2014-01-27</introducedDate>
    <title>Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <cosponsors />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to consider specified economic impacts of any regulation before issuing it. </p> <p>Directs the Board, in deciding whether and how to regulate, to assess the costs and benefits of regulatory alternatives, including the alternative of not regulating, and choose the approach that maximizes net benefits. </p> <p>Sets forth additional considerations, including market liquidity in the securities markets and global competitiveness.</p>  <p>Requires the Board, whenever it adopts or amends a regulation designated as a&quot;major rule,&quot; to make a post-adoption impact assessment, including intended and unintended consequences of the regulation.</p> <p>Requires a one-week blackout period before each meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee, until midnight of the day after the meeting, during which restrictions are imposed upon public communications by Board members and staff, with specified exceptions, regarding macroeconomic or financial developments or current or prospective monetary policy issues. </p> <p>Applies to Board members and staff the ethics standards that apply to Securities and Exchange commission (SEC) employees with respect to financial interests and transactions. Prescribes requirements for disclosure of brokerage accounts.</p> <p>Directs the Board to make publicly available on its website staff salaries and financial information.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the employee pay and pay scale used by the Board. </p> <p>Requires the Vice Chairman for Supervision to testify to Congress on the status of all pending and anticipated Board rulemakings.</p> <p>Revises requirements for Board communications with Congress. </p> <p>Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to require the Board to: (1) issue regulations for nonbank financial company stress test conditions, and (2) disclose and update publicly the aggregate number of supervisory letters sent to bank holding companies.</p> <p>Requires the Board to: (1) submit audits and performance reviews to certain congressional committees, and (2) designate as chairman of the board of directors of the Federal reserve bank and as Federal reserve agent one of either class A or class B directors with tested banking experience.</p> <p>Eliminates Class C Directors who are required to represent the public with due but not exclusive consideration to the interests of agriculture, commerce, industry, services, labor, and consumers.</p> <p>Requires the Board to choose its chairman instead of the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p> <p>Revises requirements for: (1) the terms of Board Directors, and (2) the filling of vacancies.</p> <p>Prohibits Board members and employees from international travel for purposes of performing any Board function. </p> <p>Requires the Board to notify Congress and the public before entering into negotiations with either a foreign or multinational entity. </p> <p>Amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978, and the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to require the Financial Institutions Examination Council and the Financial Stability Oversight Council, before issuing any regulation, to: (1) identify and assess the nature and source of the problem to be addressed, (2) assess the costs and benefits of available regulatory alternatives, and (3) make a post-adoption impact assessment of any major rule.</p> <p>Subjects members and employeees of both Councils to the same ethics standards and outside employment and activity requirements as govern SEC employees.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-04-01T15:54:05Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2014-01-27</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-01-27T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To improve the accountability and transparency of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-01-27T17:00:32Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-01-27</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-27</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-27</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-27</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <laws />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>1062</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>SEC Regulatory Accountability Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-05-20</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
      <item>
        <number>5018</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>Federal Reserve Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-07-30</actionDate>
          <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 26.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>113</congress>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <billNumber>3928</billNumber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

