<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <recordedVotes />
    <introducedDate>2014-09-15</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-12-03T22:27:21Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Metropolitan Planning Enhancement Act - Revises metropolitan transportation planning organization (MPO) requirements.</p> <p>Prescribes requirements for the designation of new and consolidation of multiple MPOs within a metropolitan statistical area.</p> <p>Defines &quot;consolidated metropolitan planning organization&quot; to mean a sole MPO that serves a metropolitan statistical area.</p> <p>Allows an MPO for an urbanized area with a population over 200,000 to request a high-performing MPO designation from the Secretary of Transportation (DOT). Specifies criteria the Secretary shall consider in making such designation. </p> <p>Revises certain allocations of surface transportation program funds to states for: (1) any areas with a population of fewer (under current law, non-urban areas with more) than 5,000, and (2) urbanized areas with a population over 200,000 that have a high-performing MPO.</p> <p>Makes similar changes to the transportation alternatives program.</p> <p>Extends permanently a state's obligational authority to distribute a specified amount of surface transportation program funds for federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs in urbanized areas with a population over 200,000, including those areas that have a high-performing MPO.</p> <p>Makes permanent a special rule authorizing a state to obligate up to 15% of its apportionment of surface transportation program funds for each fiscal on roads functionally classified as minor collectors in areas of less than 5,000 population.</p> <p>Revises requirements for the apportionment of state planning funds to MPOs.</p> <p>Requires a state's apportionment to be distributed in accordance with a formula that prioritizes the needs of high-performing MPOs.</p> <p>Requires metropolitan planning organizations to involve public port authorities in metropolitan freight transportation planning.</p> <p>Revises the statewide and nonmetropolitan transportation planning process for the development of statewide transportation plans and statewide transportation improvement programs for federal-aid highway projects. Makes certain changes from discretionary to mandatory with respect to such process.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to certify at least once every four years that each state has met certain requirements; and other federal laws, regulations, and orders applicable to the statewide and nonmetropolitan and the metropolitan processes.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to withhold up to 20% of a state's apportionment of funds for federal-aid highway projects and public transportation projects if the state fails to meet such certification.</p> <p>Makes similar changes to requirements for public transportation program projects.</p> <p>Eliminates the requirement that the congestion management process be addressed in the metropolitan transportation planning and statewide and nonmetropolitan transportation planning of such projects in:</p> <ul> <li>urbanized transportation management areas with a population over 200,000 individuals, and </li> <li>certain nonattainment areas for ozone or carbon monoxide.</li> </ul> <p>Revises requirements authorizing a MPO to voluntarily elect to develop multiple scenarios for consideration as part of the development of the metropolitan transportation plan for a metropolitan planning area.</p> <p>Requires a MPO to offer certain interested parties a reasonable opportunity to participate in the development and consideration of those scenarios as well as provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan.</p> <p>Prescribes requirements to require MPOs to create a performance-based target achievement process for adding projects to a transportation improvement program.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2014-09-15T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hspw12</systemCode>
              <name>Highways and Transit Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-09-16T16:12:47Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-09-15T16:03:05Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:16:25Z</updateDate>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>22</district>
        <bioguideId>F000462</bioguideId>
        <firstName>Lois</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <state>FL</state>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2119</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>F000462</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <fullName>Rep. Frankel, Lois [D-FL-22]</fullName>
        <lastName>Frankel</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <amendments />
    <title>Metropolitan Planning Enhancement Act</title>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Navigation, waterways, harbors</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public transit</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Regional and metropolitan planning</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Roads and highways</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local finance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Urban and suburban affairs and development</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-09-16</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <createDate>2014-09-16T04:46:37Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <laws />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Ms. FRANKEL of Florida:H.R. 5467.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8 (Clauses 1, 3, 7, and 18) of theUnited States Constitution, which grants Congress the powerto lay and collect taxes for the purpose of spending; toregulate commerce between the several states; and toestablish post offices and post roads.[Page H7529]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-16</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Highways and Transit Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw12</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <billNumber>5467</billNumber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001061</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-09-15</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>5</district>
        <firstName>Emanuel</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1790</lisID>
          <gpoId>8013</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C001061</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>MO</state>
        <lastName>Cleaver</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <fullName>Rep. Cleaver, Emanuel [D-MO-5]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001084</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-09-15</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>1</district>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <party>D</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8139</gpoId>
          <lisID>2055</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001084</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>RI</state>
        <lastName>Cicilline</lastName>
        <middleName>N.</middleName>
        <fullName>Rep. Cicilline, David N. [D-RI-1]</fullName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <notes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Metropolitan Planning Enhancement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To enhance the capabilities of metropolitan planning organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Metropolitan Planning Enhancement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>4834</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>GROW AMERICA Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-07-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

