<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-09-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>5</district>
        <state>TN</state>
        <firstName>JAMES</firstName>
        <lastName>COOPER</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Cooper, Jim [D-TN-5]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>C000754</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>231</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C000754</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8152</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>15</district>
        <state>OH</state>
        <firstName>Steve</firstName>
        <lastName>Stivers</lastName>
        <fullName>Rep. Stivers, Steve [R-OH-15]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>S001187</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2047</lisID>
          <gpoId>8105</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001187</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <title>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2013</title>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-12-05T20:58:47Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2013 - Provides that Department of Defense (DOD) financial statements shall cease to be covered by specified DOD financial reporting requirements upon the issuance of an unqualified audit opinion (UAO) on such statements. </p> <p>Provides that if DOD obtains a UAO on its statement of budgetary resources for any fiscal year after FY2014, the limitation on the total amount of authorizations that the Secretary of Defense may transfer pursuant to general transfer authority in the national interest in the succeeding fiscal year shall be $8 billion. Sets forth thresholds for the reprogramming of funds that shall apply to increases or decreases to the program base amount for a procurement or research program or an operation and maintenance or military personnel budget activity for a military department, defense agency, or defense field activity that obtains a UAO on its statement of budgetary resources. </p> <p>Requires additional qualifications and responsibilities of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) and certain other DOD financial management officials if DOD fails to obtain a UAO on its general fund statement of budgetary resources for FY2015 by December 31, 2015.</p> <p>Provides that if DOD fails to obtain a UAO on its general fund statement of budgetary resources for FY2018 by December 31, 2018, the reprogramming authority provided above will cease to apply. Requires, effective as of April 1, 2019, the reorganization of the position of DOD Chief Management Officer, with added qualifications and responsibilities.</p> <p>Transfers jurisdiction of the Defense Finance and Accounting Service from DOD to the Department of the Treasury and requires the Secretary of the Treasury to administer such Service.</p> <p>Provides that if a military department fails to obtain a UAO on its financial statements: (1) for FY2018 by December 31, 2018, the reprogramming authority provided above will cease to apply; and (2) for any fiscal year after 2017, amounts available to that department may not be obligated for a weapon or weapon system or platform being acquired under a major defense acquisition program for any activity beyond Milestone B approval not already obtained. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Defense to amend the acquisition guidance of DOD to place specific limits on the procurement of any enterprise resource planning business system, including a three-year limit on its total procurement time from initial obligation of funds to full deployment and sustainment.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <updateDate>2013-09-26T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. COFFMAN:H.R. 3184.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8, Clause 14 states that Congress shallhave the power ``to make rules for the government andregulation of the land and naval forces;''Article 1, Section 8, Clause 16 states that Congress shallhave the power ``to provide for organizing, arming, anddisciplining the militia;'' andArticle 1, Section 8, Clause 18 states that Congress shallhave the power ``to make all laws which shall be necessaryand proper for carrying into execution the foregoing powers.. . .''Congressional power over the finances of the Department ofDefense is an exclusive power. This includes the inherentright of Congress to direct the Department of Defense toconduct an audit of its finances and manage the manner inwhich this is conducted.[Page H5883]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Appropriations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computers and information technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Defense spending</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Defense</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Treasury</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal officials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military procurement, research, weapons development</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billNumber>3184</billNumber>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To provide for auditable financial statements for the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Coffman, Mike [R-CO-6]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Coffman</lastName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1912</lisID>
          <gpoId>7864</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
        <district>6</district>
        <state>CO</state>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:07:32Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-09-17</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>1510</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2013</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <notes />
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2013-09-27T11:33:36Z</createDate>
    <introducedDate>2013-09-26</introducedDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-09-26T14:00:25Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <congress>113</congress>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

