<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Matsui</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7810</gpoId>
          <lisID>1814</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001163</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>6</district>
        <firstName>Doris</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>M001163</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Matsui, Doris O. [D-CA-6]</fullName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <middleName>O.</middleName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Ms. MATSUI:H.R. 2293.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8, Clause 3[Page H3252]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>2293</billNumber>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-06-06T13:04:05Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-06-07T20:32:39Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hspw02</systemCode>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2013-06-06</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Flood Control Credit Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to apply credit for in-kind contributions by a non-federal interest that exceed the required non-federal cost-share for a water resources study or project, including credit for in-kind contributions provided to accelerate completion of such a study or project, toward the required non-federal cost-share for a different water resources study or project.</p> <p>Allows credit in excess of non-federal cost-share for a study or project to be approved only if: (1) the non-federal interest submits a comprehensive plan to the Secretary that identifies the studies and projects for which it intends to provide in-kind contributions for credit that is in excess of the non-federal cost share for the study or project and the studies and projects to which that excess credit would be applied, (2) the Secretary approves such plan, and (3) the total amount of credit does not exceed the total non-federal cost-share for the studies and projects in the approved plan.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to consider whether applying such credit will: (1) help to expedite the completion of a project or group of projects, (2) reduce federal government costs, and (3) aid the completion of a project that provides significant flood risk reduction or environmental benefits.</p> <p>Amends the Flood Control Act of 1970 to: </p> <ul> <li>allow a partnership agreement for the construction of a water resources project to require the Secretary to credit the value of in-kind contributions made by the non-federal interest toward the non-federal share of the cost of a project under an environmental infrastructure assistance program; </li> <li>require the Secretary and the non-federal interest, in any case in which the non-federal interest is to receive credit for the cost of construction it carried out before execution of a partnership agreement and such construction has not been carried out as of the date of enactment of this Act, to enter into an agreement under which the non-federal interest shall carry out such work prior to initiating construction or issuing a written notice to proceed for the construction; </li> <li>provide that construction that is carried out after the execution of such an agreement, and any design activities that are required for that construction, shall be eligible for credit; </li> <li>allow credit for in-kind contributions provided by a non-federal interest that are in excess of the non-federal cost share for an authorized separable element of a project to be applied toward the non-federal cost share for a different authorized separable element of the same project or toward another authorized project, within the same watershed, for which the non-federal interest has a cost share responsibility; and </li> <li>require the Secretary, to the extent that credit for in-kind contributions and credit for required land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations provided by the non-federal interest exceed the non-federal share of the cost of construction of a project other than a navigation project, to reimburse the difference to the non-federal interest. </li> </ul> <p>Requires credit for in-kind contributions authorized for a water resources project under the Flood Control Act of 1970 or a flood control project under the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 to be available for work performed by a non-federal interest on any separable element of a project following the identification by the Secretary of project alternatives as part of a feasibility study or a general or limited reevaluation report.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-06-06T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-09-25T18:53:37Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Flood Control Credit Act of 2013</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To amend the Flood Control Act of 1970 with respect to credit for in-kind contributions, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Flood Control Credit Act of 2013</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <createDate>2013-06-07T07:01:19Z</createDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <title>Flood Control Credit Act of 2013</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:04:26Z</updateDate>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2100</lisID>
          <bioguideId>L000578</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>LaMalfa</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-06-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>1</district>
        <firstName>Doug</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. LaMalfa, Doug [R-CA-1]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>L000578</bioguideId>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000559</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1973</lisID>
          <gpoId>7815</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Garamendi</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-06-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>3</district>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Garamendi, John [D-CA-3]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>G000559</bioguideId>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <introducedDate>2013-06-06</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-07</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw02</systemCode>
          <name>Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-06</actionDate>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-06</actionDate>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-06</actionDate>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Text similarities</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-10-31</actionDate>
          <text>See also H.R. 3080.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>601</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Water Resources Development Act of 2013</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-06-07</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Army Corps of Engineers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Floods and storm protection</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local finance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water resources funding</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

