<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <amendments />
    <laws />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsed14</systemCode>
          <name>Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <introducedDate>2013-05-14</introducedDate>
    <notes />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committeeReports />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Growth to Excellence Act of 2013 - Amends part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow states to measure student progress toward academic achievement standards using adaptive assessments that are computerized, aligned with grade-level academic content standards, and measure student growth above and below grade level.</p> <p>Allows states, upon the Secretary of Education's approval, to adopt an alternative accountability model requiring their local educational agencies (LEAs) and public elementary and secondary schools to achieve adequate student growth toward college and career readiness standards.</p> <p>Requires such states to: (1) adopt college and career ready academic content standards; (2) adopt college and career ready assessments that measure annual student growth in mathematics and reading or the language arts; (3) measure secondary school graduation rates; (4) assess at least two additional specified indicators of students' college or career readiness; and (5) provide a comprehensive system of accountability for schools that do not meet annual progress targets, which shall categorize schools based on student performance, include supports and consequences based on such categorization, and provide incentives for schools that consistently exceed such targets.</p> <p>Requires an alternative accountability model to establish annual progress targets for each school that: (1) aim to reduce by half, in less than six years, the difference between the percentage of students (overall and in specified student subgroups) at the top performing schools who meet the college and career readiness standards or make adequate student growth, and the percentage of such students at each school that is not a top performing school; (2) ensure that students are making adequate yearly growth to be college and career ready by the end of the 2019-2020 school year; or (3) are calculated in another manner, but result in ambitious and achievable targets for students overall and in specified student subgroups.</p> <p>Requires annual progress targets for secondary schools that: (1) aim to reduce by half, in less than six years, the difference between the percentage of students (overall and in specified student subgroups) who graduate and 90%; or (2) establish another single graduation rate goal for each specified student subgroup that is ambitious and achievable.</p> <p>Requires states using an alternative accountability model to establish a system of categorization and related interventions and rewards that groups LEAs based on their schools' and students' annual progress toward such targets.</p> <p>Describes what shall be considered adequate student growth toward college and career readiness standards.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-06-12T22:00:13Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2013-05-14T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Education</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Academic performance and assessments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billNumber>1977</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7860</gpoId>
          <lisID>1910</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000598</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>Polis</lastName>
        <district>2</district>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Jared</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>P000598</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Polis, Jared [D-CO-2]</fullName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. POLIS:H.R. 1977.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 1, All legislative Powers herein grantedshall be vested in a Congress of the United States, whichshall consist of a Senate and House of Representatives.[Page H2604]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>943</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestTitle>Growth to Excellence Act of 2013</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-05-14</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Growth to Excellence Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To establish an alternative accountability model.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Growth to Excellence Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:03:29Z</updateDate>
    <recordedVotes />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2013-07-08</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <createDate>2013-05-15T07:02:11Z</createDate>
    <title>Growth to Excellence Act of 2013</title>
    <cosponsors />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-05-14T16:00:44Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsed14</systemCode>
              <name>Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2013-07-08T20:29:36Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

