<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Wittman</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000804</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1886</lisID>
          <gpoId>8192</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
        <district>1</district>
        <firstName>Robert</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>W000804</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Wittman, Robert J. [R-VA-1]</fullName>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. WITTMAN:H.R. 3063.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, section 8 of the Constitution of the UnitedStates grants Congress the authority to enact this bill.____________________[Page H5402]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>3063</billNumber>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-08-02T13:11:45Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act&nbsp;to require the Secretary of Commerce to develop and publish at least triennially in the Federal Register (on the same schedule as the fisheries research strategic plan) a plan to conduct stock assessments for all stocks of fish for which a fishery management plan is in effect. </p> <p>Defines "stock assessment" as an evaluation of the past, present, and future status of a stock of fish, including: (1) a range of life history characteristics, including the stock's geographical boundaries, age, growth, natural mortality, sexual maturity and reproduction, feeding habits, and habitat preferences; and (2) fishing for the stock.</p> <p>Requires the plan to: (1) establish schedules for conducting initial stock assessments and updating previously conducted assessments; and (2) identify data and analysis, especially concerning recreational fishing, that would reduce uncertainty in and improve the accuracy of future stock assessments, including whether such data and analysis could be provided by nongovernmental sources,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;fishermen, fishing communities, universities, and research institutions. Provides for waivers of stock assessment requirements when the Secretary determines that the assessment is not necessary and justifies such determination in the Federal Register notice.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to develop and publish in the Federal Register guidelines to incorporate data, analysis, and stock assessments from nongovernmental sources into fisheries management decisions and to establish a registry of information providers. Requires the Secretary and Regional Fishery Management Councils to use such information as the best scientific information available in fisheries management decisions, unless otherwise determined by the science and statistical committee of such Councils.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to report to Congress&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;each fishery governed by a fishery management plan to: (1) identify the goals and methods of the applicable programs governing monitoring and enforcement of fishing subject to such plan; (2) certify which methods are most cost-effective; and (3) explain why such most-cost-effective methods are not required, if applicable.</p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary from collecting certain fishing permit fees and North Pacific Council fisheries research plan implementation fees before identifying the costs that will be recovered by such fee. </p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2013-08-02</actionDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-08-21T17:34:28Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <updateDate>2013-08-02T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require the Secretary of Commerce to develop a plan to conduct stock assessments for all stocks of fish for which a fishery management plan is in effect under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <createDate>2013-08-05T14:11:43Z</createDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <title>Healthy Fisheries through Better Science Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:07:05Z</updateDate>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Garcia, Joe [D-FL-26]</fullName>
        <lastName>Garcia</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>G000573</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2120</lisID>
          <bioguideId>G000573</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Joe</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-09-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <district>26</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <state>FL</state>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <introducedDate>2013-08-02</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-02</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-02</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <relatedBills />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-08-02</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fishes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hunting and fishing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>User charges and fees</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

