<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-07-21</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-06-05T19:00:47Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-07-21T14:35:23Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
              <name>Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2014-06-06T07:22:01Z</createDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-07-21</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
          <name>Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-05</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-05</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-05</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2014-06-05</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mrs. CAPPS:H.R. 4806.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The Constitutional authority in which this bill rests isthe power of the Congress to regulate Commerce, as enumeratedby Article I, Section 8, Clause 3 of the United StatesConstitution.[Page H5073]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>4806</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-09-25T22:11:20Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2014-06-05T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2014-06-05</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Pause for Safety Act of 2014 - Authorizes the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to make grants to to assist states in carrying out state legislation that: (1) authorizes family members or close associates of an individual to apply for, and state courts or magistrates to issue, gun violence prevention orders (prohibiting a named individual from owning, purchasing, possessing, or receiving firearms because such individual poses a significant threat of personal injury to the individual or others) and gun violence prevention warrants (directing a law enforcement officer to temporarily seize any firearm in the possession of such individual); and (2) requires each law enforcement agency of the state to comply with a procedure that requires a law enforcement officer, in conjunction with performing a wellness check (a visit to an individual's residence to assess whether the individual poses a danger to the individual or others due to a mental, behavioral, or physical condition), to check whether the individual is listed on any of the firearm and ammunition databases of the state or jurisdiction in which the individual resides. </p> <p>Requires: (1) a court issuing such an order and warrant to hold a hearing within 14 days to determine whether the individual who is the subject of the order may own, purchase, possess, or receive firearms and whether any seized firearms should be returned; (2) the state or petitioner to establish probable cause that the individual poses a significant risk of personal injury to the individual or others by owning or possessing the firearm; (3) the individual to be prohibited from possessing a firearm for up to one year if he or she is found to pose a significant threat; and (4) the firearm to be returned if the court finds that the state has not met the required standard of proof. Authorizes a law enforcement agency to seek renewal of an order if it has probable cause to believe the individual continues to pose a threat. </p> <p>Amends the federal criminal court to prohibit: (1) the sale or disposition of a firearm or ammunition to anyone subject to such an order; and (2) any person subject to such an order from owning, purchasing, possessing, or receiving any firearms.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Crime prevention</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Violent crime</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <title>Pause for Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:13:50Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Pause for Safety Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To provide family members and close associates of an individual who they fear is a danger to himself, herself, or others new tools to prevent gun violence.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Pause for Safety Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>CA</state>
        <firstName>LOIS</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>C001036</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Capps, Lois [D-CA-24]</fullName>
        <lastName>CAPPS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>24</district>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7828</gpoId>
          <lisID>1471</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001036</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <number>2445</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-06-05</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Pause for Safety Act of 2014</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <notes />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

