<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <introducedDate>2013-06-04</introducedDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-06-04T14:03:10Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-06-10T19:15:02Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestTitle>Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area Act</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>869</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-07-31</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-93.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Ms. SEWELL of Alabama:H.R. 2254.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8:``The Congress shall have Power To lay and collect Taxes,Duties, Imposts and Excises, to pay the Debts and provide forthe common Defence and general Welfare of the United States;but all Duties, Imposts and Excises shall be uniformthroughout the United States;``To borrow Money on the credit of the United States;``To regulate Commerce with foreign Nations, and among theseveral States, and with the Indian Tribes;``To establish an uniform Rule of Naturalization, anduniform Laws on the subject of Bankruptcies throughout theUnited States;``To coin Money, regulate the Value thereof and of foreignCoin, and fix the Standard of Weights and Measures;``To provide for the Punishment of counterfeiting theSecurities and current Coin of the United States;``To establish Post Offices and post Roads;``To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, bysecuring for limited Times to Authors and Inventors theexclusive Right to their respective Writings and Discoveries;``To constitute Tribunals inferior to the Supreme Court;``To define and punish Piracies and Felonies committed onthe high Seas, and Offences against the Law of Nations;``To declare War, grant Letters of Marque and Reprisal, andmake Rules concerning Captures on Land and Water;``To raise and support Armies, but no Appropriation ofMoney to that Use shall be for a longer Term than two Years;``To provide and maintain a Navy;``To make Rules for the Government and Regulation of theland and naval Forces;``To provide for calling forth the Militia to execute theLaws of the Union, suppress Insurrections and repelInvasions;``To provide for organizing, arming, and disciplining, theMilitia, and for governing such Part of them as may beemployed in the Service of the United States, reserving tothe States respectively, the Appointment of the Officers, andthe Authority of training the Militia according to thediscipline prescribed by Congress;``To exercise exclusive Legislation in all Caseswhatsoever, over such District (not exceeding ten Milessquare) as may, by Cession of particular States, and theAcceptance of Congress, become the Seat of the Government ofthe United States, and to exercise like Authority over allPlaces purchased by the Consent of the Legislature of theState in which the Same shall be, for the Erection of Forts,Magazines, Arsenals, dock-Yards, and other needfulBuildings;--And``To make all Laws which shall be necessary and proper forcarrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, and all otherPowers vested by this Constitution in the Government of theUnited States, or in any Department or Officer thereof.''[Page H3096]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Sewell, Terri A. [D-AL-7]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S001185</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1988</lisID>
          <gpoId>7792</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>S001185</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <state>AL</state>
        <lastName>Sewell</lastName>
        <district>7</district>
        <firstName>Terri</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <recordedVotes />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <committeeReports />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To establish the Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area Act</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <createDate>2013-06-05T07:01:44Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2197</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001289</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <party>R</party>
        <lastName>Byrne</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>B001289</bioguideId>
        <state>AL</state>
        <district>1</district>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Bradley</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Byrne, Bradley [R-AL-1]</fullName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2013-06-04</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-09-06T19:35:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area in Alabama. </p> <p>Designates the Center for the Study of the Black Belt at the University of West Alabama as the local coordinating entity for the Heritage Area, requires the Center to submit a management plan for the Heritage Area, and sets forth procedures for the approval or disapproval of such plan. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <updateDate>2013-06-04T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-10</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <actionDate>2013-06-04</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionDate>2013-06-04</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionDate>2013-06-04</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <amendments />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Alabama</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Historical and cultural resources</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <laws />
    <title>Alabama Black Belt National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:04:18Z</updateDate>
    <billNumber>2254</billNumber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-06-10</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

