<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Ms. LORETTA SANCHEZ of California:H.R. 4516.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:``The constitutional authority of Congress to enact thislegislation is provided by Article I, section 8 of the UnitedStates Constitution (clauses 12, 13, 14, 16, and 18), whichgrants Congress the power to raise and support an Army; toprovide and maintain a Navy; to make rules for the governmentand regulation of the land and naval forces; to provide fororganizing, arming, and disciplining the militia; and to makeall laws necessary and proper for carrying out the foregoingpowers.''[Page H3292]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <createDate>2014-04-30T07:25:26Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors />
    <title>She Is Ready Act</title>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-07-01</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsas02</systemCode>
          <name>Military Personnel Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-04-29</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-04-29</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-04-29</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <committeeReports />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:12:42Z</updateDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Defense</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military education and training</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Women's employment</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-07-01</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000030</bioguideId>
        <state>CA</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Sanchez, Loretta [D-CA-46]</fullName>
        <firstName>LORETTA</firstName>
        <district>46</district>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>SANCHEZ</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000030</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1522</lisID>
          <gpoId>7852</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <relatedBills />
    <laws />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
          <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-04-29T14:00:35Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-07-01T17:36:05Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsas02</systemCode>
              <name>Military Personnel Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-07-30T19:39:35Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>She Is Ready Act - Prohibits the Secretaries of the military departments (the Secretaries) from unduly delaying the assignment of female members of the Armed Forces to military occupational specialties, positions, and units because of the absence of a cadre or critical mass of female members available for such assignment. Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to direct the Secretaries to open for assignment of women all positions in occupations that are open to female members in any unit of the Armed Forces.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense to direct: (1) the Secretaries to validate the gender-neutral occupational standards used by the Armed Forces for the purpose of ensuring that such standards: (1) are consistent with provisions requiring performance outcome-based standards for the successful accomplishment of the necessary and required specific tasks associated with the qualifications and duties performed; (2) accurately predict performance of actual, regular, and recurring duties of a military occupation; and (3) are applied equitably to measure individual capabilities.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense to: (1) direct the Secretaries to provide greater transparency of women in service implementation plans and ensure that a statement of administration policy is created to reflect the mission of the plan and its intent on responsibly opening all jobs, positions, and units to female members of the Armed Forces; (2) promptly respond whenever one of the Secretaries submits a notice of newly opened jobs, positions, or units to female members of the Armed Forces; and (3) ensure all closed positions and units are open to female members of the Armed Forces by January 1, 2016, consistent with the Joint Memorandum issued on January 24, 2013, regarding the elimination of the 1994 Direct Ground Combat Definition and Assignment Rule.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Navy to provide Congress with information on: (1) what process and metrics were used to validate the physical standards applicable to members of the Navy and Marine Corps; and (2) Marine Corps research involving female members of the Marine Corps who volunteer for the Infantry Officers Course, the enlisted infantry training course, and the Ground Combat Element Experimental Task Force. Makes any female member of the Marine Corps who graduates from the enlisted infantry course eligible for assignment to an infantry occupational specialty. </p> <p>Requires: (1) the Secretary of the Army to permit female members of the Army to apply to Army Ranger School for leadership training opportunities, and (2) the Secretary of Defense to direct the Special Operations Command to submit to Congress the type of approach and methodology it will be using for the integration of women into the Special Operations Forces.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense to direct the Secretaries to take immediate steps to ensure that properly designed and fitted combat equipment is available and distributed to female members of the Armed Forces.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a review of Services' Outreach and Recruitment Efforts gauged toward women representation in the officer corps.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-04-29T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-04-29</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <introducedDate>2014-04-29</introducedDate>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <billNumber>4516</billNumber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>She Is Ready Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To expedite and oversee the implementation of the women in service implementation plan, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>She Is Ready Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

