<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 18.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
              <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-09-18T20:10:36Z</date>
                  <name>Discharged from</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-09-10T19:05:37Z</date>
                  <name>Hearings by</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-09-09T15:26:33Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-09-18T20:11:15Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2014-09-08T18:00:38Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2014-09-09T05:08:50Z</createDate>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>8</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 18.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-10</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <placeholderTextForH>3</placeholderTextForH>
        <prayer>1</prayer>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2014-09-08</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. HASTINGS of Washington:H.R. 5412.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, section 8, clause 18[Page H7296]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>5412</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 5412, Bureau of Reclamation Surface Water Storage Streamlining Act</title>
        <pubDate>2014-11-18T19:02:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/49789</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-02-04T19:55:10Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-09-08</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Bureau of Reclamation Surface Water Storage Streamlining Act - Sets forth provisions governing feasibility studies for surface water storage projects initiated by the Secretary of the Interior under the Reclamation Act of 1902 (project studies).</p> <p>Requires a project study initiated after enactment of this Act to: (1) result in the completion of a final feasibility report within three years; (2) have a maximum federal cost of $3 million; and (3) ensure that personnel from the local project area, region, and headquarters levels of the Bureau of Reclamation concurrently conduct the required review. Sets forth factors for extending such time line for complex projects. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary, within 90 days after the initiation of a project study, to: (1) initiate the process for completing reviews, including environmental reviews, required to be completed as part of such study; (2) convene a meeting of federal, tribal, and state agencies required to act; and (3) provide information that will enable required reviews and analyses to be conducted by other agencies in a thorough and timely manner. </p>  <p>Directs the Secretary to: (1) expedite the completion of any ongoing project study initiated before the enactment of this Act; and (2) proceed directly to preconstruction planning, engineering, and design of a project the Secretary determines is justified. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements applicable to project studies initiated after enactment of this Act for which an environmental impact statement is prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Requires the Secretary to: </p> <ul> <li> annually prepare a list of all such studies that do not have adequate funding for study completion; </li> <li>develop and implement a coordinated environmental review process for the development of such studies;</li> <li> identify, as early as practicable in such process, all federal, state, and local government agencies and Indian tribes that have jurisdiction and that are required to act, which the federal lead agency shall invite to become participating or cooperating agencies;</li> <li> issue guidance regarding the use of programmatic approaches to carry out the environmental review process; and </li> <li> establish an electronic database and issue reporting requirements to make publicly available the status and progress with respect to compliance with applicable NEPA requirements and any other federal, state, or local approval or action required for a project study.</li> </ul> <p> Sets forth the authorities and responsibilities of the joint lead agency, which may be a project sponsor, and the federal lead agency in the environmental review process, including: (1) the preparation and use of environmental documents; (2) establishing a plan for coordinating public and agency participation; (3) working with cooperating and participating agencies to identify and resolve issues that could delay process completion or result in the denial of any approval required for the project study; and (4) establishing, upon request, memoranda of agreement with the project sponsor, Indian tribes, and state and local governments to carry out the early coordination activities.</p> <p>Requires a federal jurisdictional agency to complete any required approval or decision for the environmental review process on an expeditious basis using the shortest existing applicable process. Provides for a reduction of funds for such an agency that fails to render such a decision by a specified deadline.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to: (1) survey the use by the Bureau of categorical exclusions in projects since 2005 and propose a new categorical exclusion for a category of activities if merited, and (2) establish a program to measure and report on progress made toward improving and expediting the planning and environmental review process.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to develop and submit by February 1 of each year a Report to Congress on Future Surface Water Storage Development that identifies the costs and benefits of, the non-federal interests associated with, and the support for project reports, proposed project studies, and proposed modifications to authorized surface water storage projects and project studies that are related to the missions and authorities of the Bureau, that require specific congressional authorization, that have not been congressionally authorized, that have not been included in any previous annual report, and that, if authorized, could be carried out by the Bureau.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2014-09-08T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Judicial review and appeals</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water resources funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <title>Bureau of Reclamation Surface Water Storage Streamlining Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:16:13Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Bureau of Reclamation Surface Water Storage Streamlining Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To facilitate and streamline the Bureau of Reclamation process for creating or expanding surface water storage under Reclamation law.</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Bureau of Reclamation Surface Water Storage Streamlining Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>WA</state>
        <firstName>DOC</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>H000329</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Hastings, Doc [R-WA-4]</fullName>
        <lastName>HASTINGS</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>4</district>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8799</gpoId>
          <lisID>512</lisID>
          <bioguideId>H000329</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <number>3080</number>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 113-121.</text>
          <actionDate>2014-06-10</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <type>HR</type>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <notes />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

