<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative remedies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Judicial review and appeals</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-09-28</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 172.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 159, Number 74 (Thursday, May 23, 2013)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. GOODLATTE:H.R. 2122.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 1 of the United States Constitution, inthat the legislation concerns the exercise of legislativepowers generally granted to Congress by that section,including the exercise of those powers when delegated byCongress to the Executive; Article I, Sections 8 and 9 of theUnited States Constitution, in that the legislation concernsthe exercise of specific legislative powers granted toCongress by those sections, including the exercise of thosepowers when delegated by Congress to the Executive; ArticleI, Section 8, clause 18 of the United States Constitution, inthat the legislation exercises legislative power granted toCongress by that clause ``to make all Laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof;'' and Article III of theUnited States Constitution, in that the legislation definesor affects powers of the Judiciary that are subject tolegislation by Congress.[Page H2955]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>ROBERT</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>446</lisID>
          <bioguideId>G000289</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8197</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <state>VA</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Goodlatte, Bob [R-VA-6]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>G000289</bioguideId>
        <middleName>W.</middleName>
        <district>6</district>
        <lastName>GOODLATTE</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2013-05-23T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-06-21T19:57:49Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013 - Amends the Administrative Procedure Act to revise and expand the requirements for federal agency rulemaking by requiring agencies, in making a rule, to base all preliminary and final factual determinations on evidence and to consider the legal authority under which the rule may be proposed, the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with the rule, any reasonable alternatives for the rule, and the potential costs and benefits associated with such alternatives.</p> <p>Requires agencies to publish advance notice of proposed rulemaking for major rules and for high-impact rules (rules having an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or $1 billion or more, respectively) and for rules that involve a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates, which shall include a written statement identifying the nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, the legal authority under which the rule may be proposed, the nature of and potential reasons to adopt a novel legal or policy position, and a solicitation for written data, views, or arguments from interested persons.</p> <p>Sets forth criteria for issuing major guidance (agency guidance that is likely to lead to an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or more, a major increase in cost or prices, or significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or ability to compete) or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates.</p> <p>Expands the scope of judicial review of agency rulemaking by allowing immediate review of rulemaking not in compliance with notice requirements and establishing a substantial evidence standard for affirming agency rulemaking decisions.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-05-23</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2013-09-28T14:13:13Z</updateDate>
          <name>Reported to House without amendment</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-11-25T21:41:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House without amendment</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Defines "major rule" and "major guidance" for purposes of this Act as a rule or guidance that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) determines is likely to impose: (1)&nbsp;an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or more, adjusted annually for inflation; (2)&nbsp;a major increase in costs or prices; (3)&nbsp;significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of U.S. enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises; or (4) significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy.&nbsp; Defines "high-impact rule" as a rule that the Administrator determines is likely to have an annual cost on the economy of $1 billion or more, adjusted annually for inflation.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Revises procedures for rule making under the Administrative Procedure Act (APA) to require a federal agency, in the rule making process, to make all preliminary and final factual determinations based on evidence and to consider: (1) the legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, (2) the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, (3) whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency may address with a rule and whether such rules may be amended or rescinded, (4) any reasonable alternatives for a new rule, and (5) the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules.</p> <p>Revises rule making notice requirements to require an agency to: </p> <ul> <li> publish in the Federal Register&nbsp;advance notice of proposed rule making involving a major or high-impact rule&nbsp;or a rule that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates; </li> <li> consult with the Administrator before issuing a proposed rule and after the issuance of an advance notice of proposed rule making;</li> <li> provide interested persons an opportunity to participate in the rule making process; </li> <li> hold a hearing before the adoption of any high-impact rule; </li> <li> expand requirements for the adoption of a final rule, including requiring that the agency adopt a rule only on the basis of the best evidence and at the least cost; and </li> <li> grant any interested person the right to petition for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule.&nbsp; </li> </ul> <p>Specifies the minimum amount of information that must be included in an advance notice of a proposed rule making.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to issue guidelines to promote coordination, simplification, and harmonization of agency rules during the rule making process.</p> <p>Exempts from such revised procedures rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Imposes new requirements for issuing any major guidance or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates. Authorizes the Administrator to issue guidelines for agencies in issuing major guidance or other guidance.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Provides for electronic access to transcripts of testimony and exhibits and other papers filed in a rule making proceeding. </p> <p>Requires the record of decision in a rule making proceeding to include information from a hearing under the Information Quality Act or on a high-impact rule.</p> <p>Requires an agency to grant a petition for a hearing in the case of a major rule, unless the agency reasonably determines that a hearing would not advance consideration of the rule or would unreasonably delay completion of the rule making. Exempts from this requirement rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Provides that an agency's denial of an Information Quality Act petition, or a failure&nbsp;to grant or deny&nbsp;such petition within 90 days, is reviewable by a court as a final action.&nbsp; Allows immediate judicial review of interim rules, other than in cases involving national security interests, issued without compliance with the notice requirements of this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Revises standards for the scope of judicial review of agency rule making to prohibit a court from deferring to an agency's: (1) interpretation of a rule if the agency did not comply with APA requirements, (2) determination of the costs and benefits or other economic or risk assessment if the agency failed to conform to guidelines on such determinations and assessments established by the Administrator, (3) determinations made in the adoption of an interim rule, or (4) guidance.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Defines "substantial evidence" for purposes of evaluating agency adjudications and for rule making under APA as such relevant evidence as a reasonable mind might accept as adequate to support a conclusion in light of the record considered as a whole, taking into account whatever in the record fairly detracts from the weight of the evidence relied upon by the agency to support its decision.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) Provides that the amendments made by this Act to specified provisions of federal law shall not apply to any rule makings pending or completed on the enactment date of this Act. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-09-28</actionDate>
          <versionCode>79</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
              <name>Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-07-18T13:43:25Z</date>
                  <name>Reported by</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-07-18T13:42:48Z</date>
                  <name>Markup by</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-07-09T13:47:23Z</date>
                  <name>Hearings by</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2013-06-14T17:22:30Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2013-09-29T00:05:55Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2013-07-24T21:50:10Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2013-05-23T13:00:53Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 113-237</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Peterson, Collin C. [D-MN-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>COLLIN</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>P000258</bioguideId>
        <middleName>C.</middleName>
        <state>MN</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>PETERSON</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8007</gpoId>
          <lisID>910</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000258</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>21</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>TX</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1075</lisID>
          <gpoId>8177</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>21</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Owens, William L. [D-NY-21]</fullName>
        <firstName>William</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>O000169</bioguideId>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <state>NY</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Owens</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1974</lisID>
          <gpoId>8673</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>O000169</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>6</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Coble, Howard [R-NC-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>HOWARD</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>C000556</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>NC</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>COBLE</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>211</lisID>
          <gpoId>8029</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000556</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>5</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Schrader, Kurt [D-OR-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kurt</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S001180</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>OR</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Schrader</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S001180</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1950</lisID>
          <gpoId>8118</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>6</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Bachus, Spencer [R-AL-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>SPENCER</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>B000013</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>AL</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>BACHUS</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B000013</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7791</gpoId>
          <lisID>38</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>2</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Griffin, Tim [R-AR-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tim</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>G000567</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>AR</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-06-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Griffin</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000567</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7794</gpoId>
          <lisID>1990</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>6</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Barr, Andy [R-KY-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>Andy</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>B001282</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>KY</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-06-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Barr</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B001282</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2131</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>32</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Sessions, Pete [R-TX-32]</fullName>
        <firstName>PETE</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S000250</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>TX</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>SESSIONS</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000250</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1525</lisID>
          <gpoId>8188</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>8</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Franks, Trent [R-AZ-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Trent</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>AZ</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Franks</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1707</lisID>
          <gpoId>7799</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>13</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Holding, George [R-NC-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>H001065</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>NC</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Holding</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>H001065</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2143</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>2</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Kline, John [R-MN-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>K000363</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>MN</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Kline</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1733</lisID>
          <gpoId>8002</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>K000363</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>0</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Noem, Kristi L. [R-SD-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kristi</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>N000184</bioguideId>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <state>SD</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Noem</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>N000184</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8147</gpoId>
          <lisID>2060</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>6</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Bachmann, Michele [R-MN-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michele</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>B001256</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>MN</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Bachmann</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1858</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001256</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8006</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>2</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Terry, Lee [R-NE-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>LEE</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>T000459</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>NE</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>TERRY</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8039</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>T000459</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1566</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>42</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Calvert, Ken [R-CA-42]</fullName>
        <firstName>KEN</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>C000059</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>CALVERT</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C000059</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7849</gpoId>
          <lisID>165</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>4</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Cotton, Tom [R-AR-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>C001095</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>AR</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Cotton</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2098</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001095</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>8</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Jason [R-MO-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jason</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S001195</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>MO</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Smith</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2191</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>S001195</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>1</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Crawford, Eric A. "Rick" [R-AR-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Eric</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>C001087</bioguideId>
        <middleName>A. "Rick"</middleName>
        <state>AR</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Crawford</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001087</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7793</gpoId>
          <lisID>1989</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>49</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Issa, Darrell E. [R-CA-49]</fullName>
        <firstName>DARRELL</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>I000056</bioguideId>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>ISSA</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1640</lisID>
          <gpoId>7854</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>I000056</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>24</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Marchant, Kenny [R-TX-24]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kenny</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>M001158</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>TX</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Marchant</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001158</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1806</lisID>
          <gpoId>8766</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>13</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Davis, Rodney [R-IL-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rodney</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>D000619</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>IL</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-07-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Davis</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000619</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2126</lisID>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Gibbs, Bob [R-OH-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bob</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>G000563</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <state>OH</state>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-09-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <lastName>Gibbs</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000563</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8108</gpoId>
          <lisID>2049</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/44477</url>
        <pubDate>2013-08-01T19:15:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 2122, Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/44477</url>
        <pubDate>2013-08-01T19:15:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 2122, Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/52812</url>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13T18:50:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 2122, a bill to reinstate and extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving Jennings Randolph Dam</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <recordedVotes />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <designationOfSpeakerProTempore>1</designationOfSpeakerProTempore>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <prayer>1</prayer>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <placeholderTextForH>3</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-09-28</actionDate>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 172.</text>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-09-28</actionDate>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-237.</text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-237</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/237</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-09-28</actionDate>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-237.</text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-237</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/237</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 9.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
          <name>Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
          <name>Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
          <name>Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
          <name>Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-05-23</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-05-23</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-05-23</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>12</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <createDate>2013-05-24T07:01:35Z</createDate>
    <laws />
    <introducedDate>2013-05-23</introducedDate>
    <updateDate>2018-06-05T16:23:04Z</updateDate>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To reform the process by which Federal agencies analyze and formulate new regulations and guidance documents.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 597.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>4</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestTitle>Jobs for America Act</latestTitle>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <amendments />
    <billNumber>2122</billNumber>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00172</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

