<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <cosponsors />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-26</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
          <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>2</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>6</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <title>MAP Act of 2013</title>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2013-07-25</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Medicare Abuse Prevention Act of 2013 or MAP Act of 2013 - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to increase civil money penalties, criminal fines, and prison sentences for fraud and abuse under the SSA title XVIII (Medicare) program.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to submit to Congress annual fraud reports with respect to Medicare, SSA title XIX (Medicaid), and SSA title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP).</p> <p>Amends the Small Business Jobs Act to exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act the algorithms used in predictive modeling and other analytics technology to identify and prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the Medicare fee-for-service program.</p> <p>Requires valid National Provider Identifiers for prescribers on pharmacy claims for covered Medicare part D prescription drugs.</p> <p>Requires a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor identifying a claim for reimbursement for a drug prescribed by an individual without a valid National Provider Identifier to report to the HHS Inspector General any relevant information on such a prescriber, including any invalid national provider identifiers being used to submit such claims and related records. Requires the Inspector General of HHS to provide such information to appropriate law enforcement agencies.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish procedures and rules to restrict access to the National Provider Identifier Registry in order to deter the fraudulent use of National Provider Identifiers.</p> <p>Decreases by 10% per quarter the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for a state if: (1) it is receiving a grant for a state controlled substance monitoring program through which it identifies fraud, waste, or abuse in connection with the provision of prescription drug coverage under the state Medicaid plan; and (2) the state or a political subdivision is reimbursed by a third party for expenditures related to such fraud, waste, or abuse, or for a recovered amount.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish procedures to eliminate the unnecessary collection, use, and display of Social Security account numbers of Medicare beneficiaries.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of HHS to ensure that each newly issued Medicare identification card does not display or electronically store, in an unencrypted format, a Medicare beneficiary's Social Security account number, unless the beneficiary's health insurance claim number is the beneficiary's or spouse's Social Security number, and the risk of fraudulent use of such numbers is not unacceptably high.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of HHS to prohibit the display of a Medicare beneficiary's Social Security account number in any written or electronic communication to the beneficiary unless its inclusion is essential for the operation of the Medicare program.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish a pilot program to evaluate the applicability of smart card technology to the Medicare program, and whether such cards would be effective in preventing Medicare fraud.</p> <p>Prohibits payment for an item or service under Medicaid or CHIP unless the claim contains: (1) a valid beneficiary identification number corresponding to an individual enrolled under the state plan or an applicable waiver; and (2) a valid provider identifier corresponding to a provider eligible to receive payment for furnishing such item or service.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-07-25T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-10-30T21:25:16Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. BILIRAKIS:H.R. 2828.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 1 which states that ``theCongress shall have the Power to lay and collect Taxes,Duties, Imposts and Excisese, to pay the Debts and providefor the . . . general Welfare of the United States . . .''[Page H5089]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Business records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Child health</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computers and information technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Crime prevention</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Freedom of information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health information and medical records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicaid</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicare</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Poverty and welfare assistance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Prescription drugs</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Health</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <billNumber>2828</billNumber>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>MAP Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Medicare Abuse Prevention Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to prevent fraud and abuse under the Medicare program and to require National Provider Identifiers for reimbursement of prescriptions under part D of the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>MAP Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Bilirakis, Gus M. [R-FL-12]</fullName>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <lastName>Bilirakis</lastName>
        <firstName>Gus</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>B001257</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1838</lisID>
          <gpoId>7881</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>B001257</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>R</party>
        <district>12</district>
        <state>FL</state>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:06:19Z</updateDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestTitle>Social Security Number Protection Act of 2011</latestTitle>
        <type>S</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <number>612</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-03-19</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S1954-1955)</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <notes />
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2013-07-26T05:52:56Z</createDate>
    <introducedDate>2013-07-25</introducedDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2013-07-26T16:25:06Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-07-25T13:00:10Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-07-25T13:00:15Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-07-26</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <congress>113</congress>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

