<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <committeeReports />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <createDate>2013-04-12T07:02:09Z</createDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To amend titles II and XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a Social Security Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Social Security surplus and a Medicare Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Medicare surplus, to provide for suspension of investment of amounts held in such Accounts until enactment of legislation providing for investment of the Trust Funds in investment vehicles other than obligations of the United States, and to establish a Social Security and Medicare Part A Investment Commission to make recommendations for alternative forms of investment of the Social Security and Medicare surpluses.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Social Welfare</name>
    </policyArea>
    <introducedDate>2013-04-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Financial services and investments</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government trust funds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicare</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Social security and elderly assistance</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <updateDate>2018-06-05T16:14:26Z</updateDate>
    <title>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 159, Number 48 (Thursday, April 11, 2013)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. WALBERG:H.R. 1517.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8, Clause 1--The Congress shall havePower To lay and collect Taxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises,to pay the Debts and provide for the common Defence andgeneral Welfare of the United States; but all Duties, Impostsand Excises shall be uniform throughout the United StatesArticle 1, Section 8, Clause 3--To regulate Commerce withforeign Nations, and among the several States, and with theIndian Tribes;Article 1, Section 8, Clause 14--To make Rules for theGovernment and Regulation of the land and naval Forces.[Page H1958]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <billNumber>1517</billNumber>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-23</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hswm01</systemCode>
          <name>Social Security Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2013-04-11</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-04-11</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-04-11</actionDate>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hswm01</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2013-04-23T15:06:10Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Social Security Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-04-11T04:02:40Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-04-23</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <byRequestType />
        <state>MI</state>
        <lastName>Walberg</lastName>
        <bioguideId>W000798</bioguideId>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Walberg, Tim [R-MI-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tim</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1855</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000798</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7992</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <laws />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to establish in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund a Social Security Surplus Protection Account to hold the Social Security surplus for the fiscal year of the sum of Social Security taxes collected, as well as the aggregate increase in certain tax liabilities, over the sum of benefits paid.</p> <p>Establishes in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund a Medicare Surplus Protection Account to hold amounts equivalent to the Medicare part A surplus for the fiscal year of the sum of hospital insurance taxes collected over the sum of Medicare part A benefits paid.</p> <p>Denies the availability of the balance in either Account for investment by the Managing Trustee.</p> <p>Establishes in the executive branch a Social Security and Medicare Part A Investment Commission to study the most effective vehicles for investment of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund (other than investment in the form of U.S. obligations resulting in the transfer of Trust Fund assets to the general fund of the Treasury).</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2013-04-11</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-04-11T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-04-23T21:15:26Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <cosponsors />
    <recordedVotes />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to establish a Social Security Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Social Security surplus, to provide for suspension of investment of amounts held in the Account until enactment of legislation providing for investment of the Trust Fund in investment vehicles other than obligations of the United States, and to establish a Social Security Investment Commission to make recommendations for alternative forms of investment of the Social Security surplus in the Trust Fund.</latestTitle>
        <number>370</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

