<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <cosponsors />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Public Online Information Act of 2014</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To establish an advisory committee to issue nonbinding governmentwide guidelines on making public information available on the Internet, to require publicly available Government information held by the executive branch to be made available on the Internet, to express the sense of Congress that publicly available information held by the legislative and judicial branches should be available on the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Public Online Information Act of 2014</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <notes />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Rep. Israel, Steve [D-NY-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>STEVE</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>I000057</bioguideId>
        <district>3</district>
        <state>NY</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>I000057</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8063</gpoId>
          <lisID>1663</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>ISRAEL</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. ISRAEL:H.R. 4312.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The legislature power vested in Congress by Article I ofthe Constitution to conduct oversight of executive agencies,and the ``Necessary and Proper'' clause found in Article I,section 8, c1.18.[Page H2696]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-03-26</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <title>Public Online Information Act of 2014</title>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-03-26</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-03-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-03-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:11:55Z</updateDate>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-03-26T14:02:45Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <laws />
    <introducedDate>2014-03-26</introducedDate>
    <billNumber>4312</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Freedom of information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Internet and video services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Legal fees and court costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <createDate>2014-03-27T07:22:40Z</createDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-03-13</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>549</number>
        <latestTitle>Public Online Information Act of 2013</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2014-03-26</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Public Online Information Act of 2014 - Establishes a Public Online Information Advisory Committee to: (1) coordinate and encourage the government's efforts to make information from all three branches of government available on the Internet, and (2) issue and update nonbinding guidelines on how the government should make public information available.</p> <p>Directs the government to make public records available on the Internet at no charge, except as imposed by federal law before this Act's enactment. Requires: (1) public records to be permanently available on the Internet; (2) current information technology capabilities to be applied to the means by which records are made available and to the formats in which they are available; and (3) each agency to publish on the Internet a comprehensive, searchable, machine processable list of all records it makes publicly available.</p> <p>Delineates the roles of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government, and the chief information officers of independent regulatory agencies, including granting narrow case-by-case exceptions to the Internet publication requirement if an agency requests an exception and demonstrates that: (1) there is a clear and convincing reason for the record to not be made available on the Internet, and (2) on balance the harm caused by disclosure significantly outweighs the public's interest in having the record available on the Internet. </p> <p>Directs the Inspector General of each agency to conduct periodic reviews regarding agency compliance with Internet publication requirements. Sets forth provisions regarding enforcement of public access by private individuals or organizations.</p> <p>Urges: (1) judicial and legislative agencies to adopt or adapt the Advisory Committee's recommendations, and (2) the Government Printing Office (GPO) to make all of its publications permanently available on the Internet in a multiplicity of formats.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-03-26T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-05-02T19:53:13Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

