<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:17:15Z</updateDate>
    <billNumber>5704</billNumber>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Holt, Rush [D-NJ-12]</fullName>
        <middleName>D.</middleName>
        <bioguideId>H001032</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>H001032</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1580</lisID>
          <gpoId>8054</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <lastName>HOLT</lastName>
        <district>12</district>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <firstName>RUSH</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-11-13T15:01:45Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Master Teacher Corps Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To amend title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a Master Teacher Corp program.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Master Teacher Corps Act</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <createDate>2014-11-14T05:17:20Z</createDate>
    <notes />
    <title>Master Teacher Corps Act</title>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Education</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wages and earnings</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-03-30T19:46:37Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2014-11-13T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Master Teacher Corps Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to consortia of local educational agencies (LEAs), states, or LEAs and states, acting in partnership with institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations to establish a Master Teacher Corps program.</p> <p>Requires the grants to be used to: </p> <ul> <li>select exemplary elementary and secondary school teachers for membership in the program;</li> <li>provide master teachers with compensation that supplements their base salary;</li> <li> provide research-based professional development;</li> <li> coordinate master teachers' instructional leadership, mentorship, training, and coaching roles, including by hiring substitute teachers to fill-in for master teachers who are working with other teachers;</li> <li> facilitate efforts to involve master teachers in policy decisions at the LEA, state, and regional levels;</li> <li> defray the educational costs associated with master teachers fulfilling their responsibilities; </li> <li> track the program's effectiveness and impact; and </li> <li> support other activities that advance the program.</li> </ul> <p>Requires teachers selected as master teachers to: (1) have at least five years of full-time experience as elementary or secondary school teachers, and (2) have earned the highest rating on their state or local evaluations for the majority of their teaching years.</p> <p>Requires master teachers to be selected based on their:</p> <ul> <li> ability to enhance student achievement and tailor instruction to individual student needs;</li> <li> ability to address adult learners in professional development;</li> <li> ability to successfully collaborate with teachers, school leaders, and staff;</li> <li>skill in promoting teacher reflection through formative assessment processes;</li> <li>strong interpersonal and oral and written communication skills;</li> <li> record of school leadership;</li> <li>participation in student extracurricular activities and professional and school outreach activities;</li> <li> record of teaching students not on grade level or not on track to graduate college and career-ready; and</li> <li>measurable ability, using various indicators.</li> </ul> <p>Requires grantees to ensure that not more than 20% of the teachers in their participating area are members of the Corps.</p> <p>Provides for the participation of private teachers as master teachers, but makes them ineligible for compensation under the program.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, to: (1) evaluate the Master Teacher Corps program; (2) identify successes, best practices, and areas for improvement; and (3) disseminate the evaluation's findings.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <introducedDate>2014-11-13</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. HOLT:H.R. 5704.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I of the United States Constitution[Page H7979]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <laws />
    <committeeReports />
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
        <committee>
          <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-11-13</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

