<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-419.</text>
          <actionDate>2014-07-09</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2503</number>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:14:23Z</updateDate>
    <billNumber>4924</billNumber>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Gosar, Paul A. [R-AZ-4]</fullName>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <bioguideId>G000565</bioguideId>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1992</lisID>
          <gpoId>7798</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>G000565</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
        <lastName>Gosar</lastName>
        <district>4</district>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Paul</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <latestAction>
      <links>
        <link>
          <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/4924/text/pl</url>
          <name>Public Law No: 113-223</name>
        </link>
      </links>
      <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-223.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Barber, Ron [D-AZ-2]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>2</district>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8368</gpoId>
          <lisID>2093</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001279</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>B001279</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Barber</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Franks, Trent [R-AZ-8]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>8</district>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1707</lisID>
          <gpoId>7799</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Trent</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Franks</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Grijalva, Raul M. [D-AZ-3]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <district>3</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1708</lisID>
          <bioguideId>G000551</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7804</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Raul</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>G000551</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Grijalva</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Kirkpatrick, Ann [D-AZ-1]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>1</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1907</lisID>
          <bioguideId>K000368</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7220</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Ann</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>K000368</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Kirkpatrick</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Salmon, Matt [R-AZ-5]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>5</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1009</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S000018</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>MATT</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>S000018</bioguideId>
        <lastName>SALMON</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Schweikert, David [R-AZ-6]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>6</district>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1994</lisID>
          <gpoId>7802</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001183</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>S001183</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Schweikert</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Sinema, Kyrsten [D-AZ-9]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>9</district>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S001191</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2099</lisID>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>Kyrsten</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>S001191</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Sinema</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-06-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Pastor, Ed [D-AZ-7]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>7</district>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>P000099</bioguideId>
          <lisID>893</lisID>
          <gpoId>7801</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <firstName>ED</firstName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>P000099</bioguideId>
        <lastName>PASTOR</lastName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
              <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-11-19T17:13:52Z</date>
                  <name>Discharged from</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-09-19T18:58:51Z</date>
                  <name>Hearings by</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <date>2014-06-26T20:33:49Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-12-01T21:23:23Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2014-11-19T17:14:38Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2014-06-20T13:01:05Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Title</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Enacted</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement and the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement, to provide for the lease of certain land located within Planet Ranch on the Bill Williams River in the State of Arizona to benefit the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program, and to provide for the settlement of specific water rights claims in the Bill Williams River watershed in the State of Arizona.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <createDate>2014-06-21T04:47:38Z</createDate>
    <notes />
    <title>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00478</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Native Americans</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Arizona</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Indian claims</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Indian lands and resources rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/49831</url>
        <pubDate>2014-12-05T15:31:39Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4924, Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 - Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement between the Hualapai Tribe, the Department of of the Interior, the Arizona Game and Fish Commission, the Arizona Department of Water Resources, and the Freeport Minerals Corporation. </p> <p> Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement between the Tribe, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, and Freeport Minerals Corporation. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Interior to execute both agreements. </p>  <p> <p>Sets forth provisions regarding the waiver, release, and retention of specified water rights claims. </p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-06-20T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-11-28T16:41:08Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement) entered into by the Hualapai Tribe (Tribe), its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), the Arizona Department of Water Resources, the Freeport Minerals Corporation (Corporation), and the Arizona Game and Fish Commission; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to execute the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to also execute a conditional withdrawal of the Department of the Interior's objections to specified applications by the Corporation to sever and transfer certain water rights from: (1) Lincoln Ranch and Planet Ranch to the Wikieop Wellfield for use at the Bagdad Mine Complex and Bagdad Townsite, and (2) portions of Planet Ranch to new locations within that Ranch. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Hualapai Tribe Agreement) entered into by the Tribe, its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, and the Corporation; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to execute the Hualapai Tribe Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes the Corporation's contribution to the economic development fund of the Tribe, as provided for in the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, to be used by the Tribe for the limited purpose of facilitating settlement of the Tribe's claims for Colorado River water rights by enabling the Tribe to: (1) acquire Colorado River water rights to increase the security of the Tribe's water rights, and (2) otherwise facilitate the use of water on the Hualapai Reservation. </p> <p>Requires the Tribe to use those acquired water rights only: (1) to irrigate acquired appurtenant land or for storage in accordance with federal and state law in a permitted recharge facility in Arizona, subject to specified conditions. Terminates these use limitations on the earlier of: (1) the date the Hualapai Tribe Agreement becomes enforceable, or (2) December 31, 2039.</p> <p>Provides that if the Hualapai Tribe Agreement does not become enforceable by December 31, 2039, any Colorado River water rights acquired by the Tribe with the Corporation's contribution to its economic development fund is to be counted toward the Tribe's clams for Colorado River water rights in any subsequent settlement or adjudication of those claims.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Provides for the waiver, release, and retention of specified water rights claims under both Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the waiver and release of specified claims by the United States and the Tribe against the Corporation, pursuant to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, for:</p> <ul> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 82 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel;</li> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 312 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 2;</li> <li>tribal water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 3; and</li> <li> injuries to federal or Indian water rights resulting from the diversion of water by the Corporation from the Wikieup Wellfield or the Freeport Groundwater Wells, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Tribe and the United States as trustee for the Tribe to waive and release their claims against the Corporation, pursuant to the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, for past, present, and future injuries to water rights resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the Tribe, in consideration of the benefits provided to it under both Agreements, to waive and release its claims against the United States for:</p> <ul> <li>all past, present, and future Parcel 3 water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year that the United States asserted or could have asserted against any party to either Agreement;</li> <li>all past, present, and future water rights associated with Parcel 3 arising from the withdrawal of a protest against the Corporation's application to sever and transfer certain water rights referenced in the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement; and</li> <li>injuries to water rights arising after the enforceability date associated with Parcel 3 resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed in a manner that does not violate the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7) Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to allow any party to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement to commence a civil action relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of: (1) the Bill Williams River water rights Settlement Act of 2014, or (2) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement. Requires those actions to be brought in the U.S. District Court for the District of Arizona or in a state court where a pending action has been brought to adjudicate the water rights associated with the Bill Williams River system and source.</p> <p>Waives the sovereign immunity of the Tribe and the United States acting as trustee for the Tribe, but only for the purpose of interpreting or enforcing the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, or the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to comply with all applicable federal environmental laws in implementing the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, and this Act.</p> <p>Provides that the Secretary's execution of those Agreements shall not constitute a major federal action for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) Sets the enforceability date for such Agreements as the date the Secretary publishes specified findings in the Federal Register that certain actions have been taken in compliance with the terms of such Agreements and this Act.</p> <p>Provides for the repeal of this Act if the Secretary does not publish such findings by: (1) December 31, 2015; or (2) 14 days after a later date agreed to by the Tribe, the Secretary, and the Corporation, after providing reasonable notice to Arizona.</p> </p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-12-01T15:43:34Z</updateDate>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-02-18T16:29:07Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on December 1, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement) entered into by the Hualapai Tribe (Tribe), its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), the Arizona Department of Water Resources, the Freeport Minerals Corporation (Corporation), and the Arizona Game and Fish Commission; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to execute the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to also execute a conditional withdrawal of the Department of the Interior's objections to specified applications by the Corporation to sever and transfer certain water rights from: (1) Lincoln Ranch and Planet Ranch to the Wikieop Wellfield for use at the Bagdad Mine Complex and Bagdad Townsite, and (2) portions of Planet Ranch to new locations within that Ranch. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Hualapai Tribe Agreement) entered into by the Tribe, its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, and the Corporation; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to execute the Hualapai Tribe Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes the Corporation's contribution to the economic development fund of the Tribe, as provided for in the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, to be used by the Tribe for the limited purpose of facilitating settlement of the Tribe's claims for Colorado River water rights by enabling the Tribe to: (1) acquire Colorado River water rights to increase the security of the Tribe's water rights, and (2) otherwise facilitate the use of water on the Hualapai Reservation. </p> <p>Requires the Tribe to use those acquired water rights only: (1) to irrigate acquired appurtenant land or for storage in accordance with federal and state law in a permitted recharge facility in Arizona, subject to specified conditions. Terminates these use limitations on the earlier of: (1) the date the Hualapai Tribe Agreement becomes enforceable, or (2) December 31, 2039.</p> <p>Provides that if the Hualapai Tribe Agreement does not become enforceable by December 31, 2039, any Colorado River water rights acquired by the Tribe with the Corporation's contribution to its economic development fund is to be counted toward the Tribe's clams for Colorado River water rights in any subsequent settlement or adjudication of those claims.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Provides for the waiver, release, and retention of specified water rights claims under both Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the waiver and release of specified claims by the United States and the Tribe against the Corporation, pursuant to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, for:</p> <ul> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 82 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel;</li> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 312 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 2;</li> <li>tribal water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 3; and</li> <li> injuries to federal or Indian water rights resulting from the diversion of water by the Corporation from the Wikieup Wellfield or the Freeport Groundwater Wells, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Tribe and the United States as trustee for the Tribe to waive and release their claims against the Corporation, pursuant to the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, for past, present, and future injuries to water rights resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the Tribe, in consideration of the benefits provided to it under both Agreements, to waive and release its claims against the United States for:</p> <ul> <li>all past, present, and future Parcel 3 water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year that the United States asserted or could have asserted against any party to either Agreement;</li> <li>all past, present, and future water rights associated with Parcel 3 arising from the withdrawal of a protest against the Corporation's application to sever and transfer certain water rights referenced in the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement; and</li> <li>injuries to water rights arising after the enforceability date associated with Parcel 3 resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed in a manner that does not violate the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7) Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to allow any party to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement to commence a civil action relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of: (1) the Bill Williams River water rights Settlement Act of 2014, or (2) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement. Requires those actions to be brought in the U.S. District Court for the District of Arizona or in a state court where a pending action has been brought to adjudicate the water rights associated with the Bill Williams River system and source.</p> <p>Waives the sovereign immunity of the Tribe and the United States acting as trustee for the Tribe, but only for the purpose of interpreting or enforcing the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, or the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to comply with all applicable federal environmental laws in implementing the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, and this Act.</p> <p>Provides that the Secretary's execution of those Agreements shall not constitute a major federal action for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) Sets the enforceability date for such Agreements as the date the Secretary publishes specified findings in the Federal Register that certain actions have been taken in compliance with the terms of such Agreements and this Act.</p> <p>Provides for the repeal of this Act if the Secretary does not publish such findings by: (1) December 31, 2015; or (2) 14 days after a later date agreed to by the Tribe, the Secretary, and the Corporation, after providing reasonable notice to Arizona.</p> </p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-12-02T12:15:40Z</updateDate>
          <name>Passed Senate without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>82</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Passed Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-02-18T16:29:18Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-12-02</actionDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it passed the House on December 1, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p>Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement) entered into by the Hualapai Tribe (Tribe), its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), the Arizona Department of Water Resources, the Freeport Minerals Corporation (Corporation), and the Arizona Game and Fish Commission; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to execute the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to also execute a conditional withdrawal of the Department of the Interior's objections to specified applications by the Corporation to sever and transfer certain water rights from: (1) Lincoln Ranch and Planet Ranch to the Wikieop Wellfield for use at the Bagdad Mine Complex and Bagdad Townsite, and (2) portions of Planet Ranch to new locations within that Ranch. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms: (1) the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement (Hualapai Tribe Agreement) entered into by the Tribe, its members and allottees, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, and the Corporation; and (2) any amendment to that Agreement that is executed to make it consistent with this Act. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to execute the Hualapai Tribe Agreement and any amendment to that Agreement that is necessary to make it consistent with this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes the Corporation's contribution to the economic development fund of the Tribe, as provided for in the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, to be used by the Tribe for the limited purpose of facilitating settlement of the Tribe's claims for Colorado River water rights by enabling the Tribe to: (1) acquire Colorado River water rights to increase the security of the Tribe's water rights, and (2) otherwise facilitate the use of water on the Hualapai Reservation. </p> <p>Requires the Tribe to use those acquired water rights only: (1) to irrigate acquired appurtenant land or for storage in accordance with federal and state law in a permitted recharge facility in Arizona, subject to specified conditions. Terminates these use limitations on the earlier of: (1) the date the Hualapai Tribe Agreement becomes enforceable, or (2) December 31, 2039.</p> <p>Provides that if the Hualapai Tribe Agreement does not become enforceable by December 31, 2039, any Colorado River water rights acquired by the Tribe with the Corporation's contribution to its economic development fund is to be counted toward the Tribe's clams for Colorado River water rights in any subsequent settlement or adjudication of those claims.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Provides for the waiver, release, and retention of specified water rights claims under both Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the waiver and release of specified claims by the United States and the Tribe against the Corporation, pursuant to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, for:</p> <ul> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 82 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel;</li> <li>Indian allottees' water rights in excess of 312 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 2;</li> <li>tribal water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year on a specified Parcel 3; and</li> <li> injuries to federal or Indian water rights resulting from the diversion of water by the Corporation from the Wikieup Wellfield or the Freeport Groundwater Wells, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Tribe and the United States as trustee for the Tribe to waive and release their claims against the Corporation, pursuant to the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, for past, present, and future injuries to water rights resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed, provided such a diversion occurring after the enforceability date of the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch and Hualapai Tribe Agreements does not violate those Agreements.</p> <p>Authorizes the Tribe, in consideration of the benefits provided to it under both Agreements, to waive and release its claims against the United States for:</p> <ul> <li>all past, present, and future Parcel 3 water rights in excess of 300 acre-feet per year that the United States asserted or could have asserted against any party to either Agreement;</li> <li>all past, present, and future water rights associated with Parcel 3 arising from the withdrawal of a protest against the Corporation's application to sever and transfer certain water rights referenced in the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement; and</li> <li>injuries to water rights arising after the enforceability date associated with Parcel 3 resulting from the Corporation's diversion of water from the Bill Williams River watershed in a manner that does not violate the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 7) Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to allow any party to the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement to commence a civil action relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of: (1) the Bill Williams River water rights Settlement Act of 2014, or (2) the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement. Requires those actions to be brought in the U.S. District Court for the District of Arizona or in a state court where a pending action has been brought to adjudicate the water rights associated with the Bill Williams River system and source.</p> <p>Waives the sovereign immunity of the Tribe and the United States acting as trustee for the Tribe, but only for the purpose of interpreting or enforcing the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, or the Hualapai Tribe Agreement.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to comply with all applicable federal environmental laws in implementing the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Agreement, the Hualapai Tribe Agreement, and this Act.</p> <p>Provides that the Secretary's execution of those Agreements shall not constitute a major federal action for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) Sets the enforceability date for such Agreements as the date the Secretary publishes specified findings in the Federal Register that certain actions have been taken in compliance with the terms of such Agreements and this Act.</p> <p>Provides for the repeal of this Act if the Secretary does not publish such findings by: (1) December 31, 2015; or (2) 14 days after a later date agreed to by the Tribe, the Secretary, and the Corporation, after providing reasonable notice to Arizona.</p> </p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2014-12-17T04:59:58Z</updateDate>
          <name>Public Law</name>
          <versionCode>49</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-02-18T16:29:25Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <introducedDate>2014-06-20</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. GOSAR:H.R. 4924.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:This legislation is constitutionally appropriate pursuantto Article I, Section 8, Clause 3 (the Commerce Clause) whichgrants Congress the power to regulate Commerce with foreignNations, and among several states and with the Indian Tribes;Article II, Section 2, Clause 2 (the Treaty Clause) whichgives the President the Power to make Treaties; Article IV,Section 3, Clause 2 (the Property Clause) which givesCongress the Power to make all Rules and Regulationsrespecting the Territory or other Property belonging to theUnited States.The Supreme Court, in Winters v. United States (1901),reasoned that an Indian Tribe's water rights are establishedwhen the reservation is created, regardless of whether theTribe actually uses the water on that reservation at thattime. The Act settles water right claims of the HualapaiTribe and is thus constitutionally permissible.[Page H5598]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <laws>
      <item>
        <type>Public Law</type>
        <number>113-223</number>
      </item>
    </laws>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 113-638</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
        <type>President</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Public Law No: 113-223</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/4924/text/pl</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 113-223.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Public Law No: 113-223</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/4924/text/pl</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 113-223.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
        <type>President</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
        <type>President</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-03</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-02</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S6272</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/senate-section/page/S6272</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S6272)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S6272</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/senate-section/page/S6272</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S6272)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:31:50</actionTime>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:31:48</actionTime>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H8181-8185</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H8181-8185</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H8181-8185)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:31:48</actionTime>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H8181-8185</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H8181-8185</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H8181-8185)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:24:35</actionTime>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 4924</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/4924</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4924.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:24:31</actionTime>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H8181-8186</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H8181-8186</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H8181-8186)</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:24:10</actionTime>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 478.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-638</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/638</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-638.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-12-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 113-638</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/638</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-638.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-26</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
          <name>Water, Power and Oceans Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>3</senate>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>17</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <passedOrAgreedToInSenateDayOf>1</passedOrAgreedToInSenateDayOf>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <presentedToPresident>1</presentedToPresident>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <placeholderTextForE>3</placeholderTextForE>
        <passedAgreedToInSenate>1</passedAgreedToInSenate>
        <prayer>1</prayer>
        <becamePublicLaw>2</becamePublicLaw>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <sentToHouse>1</sentToHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>3</placeholderTextForH>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

