<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. BUCSHON:H.R. 5035.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 3: The Congress shall havepower to regulate commerce with foreign nations, and amongthe several states, and with the Indian tribes;Article I, Section 8, Clause 5: To coin Money, regulate theValue thereof, and of foreign Coin, and fix the Standard ofWeights and Measures; andArticle I, Section 8, Clause 18: The Congress shall havepower to make all Laws which shall be necessary and properfor carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, and allother Powers vested by this Constitution in the Government ofthe United States, or in any Department or Officer thereof.[Page H6035]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <createDate>2014-07-10T05:01:18Z</createDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <state>TX</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1075</lisID>
          <gpoId>8177</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <district>21</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>Chris</firstName>
        <state>NY</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Collins, Chris [R-NY-27]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2151</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001092</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>C001092</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <district>27</district>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <title>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>9</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>1</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-07-23</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:58:24</actionTime>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H6597-6599)</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:58:23</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H6597-6599</url>
            <name>H6597-6599</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H6597-6599)</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:58:23</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H6597-6599</url>
            <name>H6597-6599</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5035.</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:51:44</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/113th-congress/house-bill/5035</url>
            <name>H.R. 5035</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H6597-6601)</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:51:42</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-160/house-section/page/H6597-6601</url>
            <name>H6597-6601</name>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Mr. Bucshon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>15:51:19</actionTime>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-09</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-09</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionDate>2014-07-09</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <committeeReports />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:14:51Z</updateDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Advisory bodies</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Building construction</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Commerce</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Education programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Industrial policy and productivity</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Manufacturing</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>National Security Agency</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Performance measurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Protection of officials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research administration and funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Science and engineering education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Small business</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Technology transfer and commercialization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Vocational and technical education</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <notes />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-07-23</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001275</bioguideId>
        <state>IN</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Bucshon, Larry [R-IN-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Larry</firstName>
        <district>8</district>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Bucshon</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2018</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001275</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7947</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <relatedBills />
    <laws />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-07-23T20:40:49Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        </item>
        <item>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2014-07-09T14:00:05Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2014-07-09</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-07-09T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-11-18T13:03:53Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Reauthorizes the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) for FY2014-FY2015. </p> <p>Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to authorize the Director of the NIST to: (1) serve as the President's principal advisor on standards policy pertaining to the nation's technological competitiveness and innovation ability, (2) support scientific and technical conferences, and (3) perform pre-competitive measurement research with institutions of higher education and industry.</p> <p>Revises requirements for research fellowships. Authorizes the NIST Director to support, promote, and coordinate activities and efforts to enhance awareness and understanding of measurement sciences, standards, and technology. Eliminates the manufacturing fellowship program and the teacher science and technology enhancement program.</p> <p>Requires the Director to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a review of NIST laboratory programs. </p> <p>Directs NIST to contract with the National Research Council (NRC) to assess the technical quality and impact of the work conducted at NIST laboratories. (Currently, NIST is authorized to contract with the NRC.)</p> <p> Makes revisions to the program known as the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership. Adds as a purpose of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Centers the transfer of best business practices. </p> <p>Removes the National Security Agency (NSA) from the list of agencies that NIST must consult in developing standards and guidelines for information systems. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2014-07-22</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-07-22T15:56:53Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>81</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Passed House without amendment</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-01-06T22:21:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Reauthorizes the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) through FY2015. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to authorize the Director of the NIST to: (1) serve as the President's principal advisor on standards policy pertaining to technological competitiveness and innovation ability, (2) facilitate standards-related information sharing and cooperation between federal agencies, (3) support scientific and technical conferences, and (4) perform pre-competitive measurement research with institutions of higher education and industry. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Revises the membership of the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology, including by requiring that at least two-thirds of members be from U.S. industry. Authorizes the Committee to consult with the National Research Council (NRC) in making recommendations regarding general policy for NIST. </p> <p>Removes the requirement that the Technology Innovation Program be included in the Committee's annual reports on policy issues or matters affecting NIST. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to undertake activities to protect NIST buildings and other plant facilities, equipment, and property and persons located in them or associated with them. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Revises requirements for research fellowships. Authorizes the Director to support, promote, and coordinate activities and efforts to enhance awareness and understanding of measurement sciences, standards, and technology. Requires the Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program to include no fewer than 20 fellows per fiscal year (currently, no fewer than 20 nor more than 120 new fellows per fiscal year). Removes provisions for the separate manufacturing fellowship and teacher science and technology enhancement programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) Requires the three-year programmatic planning document for NIST to also describe how the Director is addressing recommendations from the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) Requires the Director to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a review of NIST laboratory programs. </p> <p>Directs NIST to contract with the NRC to assess the technical quality and impact of the work conducted at NIST laboratories. (Currently, NIST is authorized to contract with the NRC for advice and studies to serve industry and science.) </p>   <p>Allows NIST to also contract with the NRC to conduct additional assessments of NIST programs and projects that involve collaboration across NIST laboratories and centers and assessments of selected topics. </p>  <p>(Sec. 9) Makes revisions to the program known as the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership. Adds as a purpose of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Centers the transfer of best business practices.</p> <p>Includes as an objective of the Centers: (1) the provision of area career and technical education schools of information about the job skills needed in small and medium-sized manufacturing businesses in the regions they serve (currently provided only to community colleges); and (2) the promotion and expansion of certification systems offered through industry, associations, and local colleges. </p> <p>Requires the activities of the Centers to include the facilitation of collaborations and partnerships between small and medium-sized manufacturing companies and community colleges and area career and technical education schools to help them better understand the specific needs of manufacturers and to help manufacturers better understand the skill sets that students learn in the programs offered by those institutions. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary to provide financial support to any Center created under the Partnership (currently, limited to six years). </p> <p>Instructs the Secretary to implement, review, and update regulations related to the Partnership at least once every three years. </p> <p>Revises cost-sharing requirements for the receipt by an applicant of financial assistance under the Partnership. </p>  <p>Bars the Secretary from providing funding to a Center unless it has received a positive evaluation. </p> <p>Requires a Center to undergo an independent review in its eighth year of operation. </p> <p>Requires the Director, if a recipient of a Center award has received financial assistance for 10 consecutive years, to conduct a new competition to select an operator for the Center consistent with the plan required by this Act. Makes incumbent Center operators in good standing eligible to compete for the new award. </p> <p>Requires the Director to: (1) transmit to Congress a plan for how NIST will conduct reviews, assessments, and reapplication competitions; and (2) contract with an independent organization to assess the implementation of the reapplication competition process. </p> <p>Requires the Director to report to Congress information on the first and second years of operations for Centers operating from new competitions or recompetition as compared to longstanding Centers.</p> <p>Applies the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to confidential information obtained by the government on the business operation of any participant in a Partnership program or of a client of a Center and trade secrets possessed by any client of a Center. </p> <p>Requires each Center's advisory boards to institute a conflict of interest policy that ensures representation of local small and medium-sized manufacturers in the Center's region. Prohibits board members from serving or providing services to the Center or serving on more than one Center's oversight board simultaneously. </p> <p>Requires the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Board to consist of no fewer than 10 members (currently, 10 members), at least one of whom represents a community college. </p> <p>Requires the Director, under the competitive grant program, to select proposals that will promote the transfer and commercialization of research and technology from institutions of higher education, national laboratories, and nonprofit research institutes. </p>  <p>(Sec. 10) Eliminates requirements for annual reports on enterprise integration standardization and implementation activities and on the Technology Innovation Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 11) Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to remove the 75% limitation on the total amount of certain grants and cooperative agreements to assist activities consistent with such Act, including activities performed by individuals. </p> <p>(Sec. 12) Removes the National Security Agency (NSA) from the list of agencies that NIST must consult in developing standards and guidelines for information systems. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Passed House without amendment</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <recordedVotes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <introducedDate>2014-07-09</introducedDate>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <billNumber>5035</billNumber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To reauthorize the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>NIST Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

