<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills />
    <title>More Water and Security for Californians Act</title>
    <createDate>2013-05-10T07:02:10Z</createDate>
    <cosponsors />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2014-09-09</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <amendments />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Aquaculture</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>California</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fishes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 159, Number 65 (Thursday, May 9, 2013)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. COSTA:H.R. 1927.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 3 of the United StatesConstitution.[Page H2569]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001059</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1774</lisID>
          <gpoId>7825</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C001059</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Costa, Jim [D-CA-16]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <district>16</district>
        <lastName>Costa</lastName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/52922</url>
        <title>H.R. 1927, African American Civil Rights Network Act of 2017</title>
        <pubDate>2017-07-17T12:46:29Z</pubDate>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <laws />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>More Water and Security for Californians Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To provide congressional direction for implementation of the Endangered Species Act as it relates to operation of the Central Valley Project and the California State Water Project and for water relief in the State of California.</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>More Water and Security for Californians Act</title>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Hearings by</name>
              <date>2014-09-09T15:27:13Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-05-09T13:05:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <billNumber>1927</billNumber>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2013-05-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-05-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2013-05-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <introducedDate>2013-05-09</introducedDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <recordedVotes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>More Water and Security for Californians Act - Deems requirements of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 relating to operations of the Central Valley Project and the California State Water Project to be satisfied with regard to the species and their critical habitat covered by the biological opinions for the operations of such Projects issued by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) if: </p> <ul> <li> the alternatives described in that portion of the biological opinions entitled "Reasonable and Prudent Alternatives" are implemented; and </li> <li> the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce ensure that: (1) between December 1 and June 30, neither such biological opinion shall restrict flow in Old and Middle Rivers to a 14-day average of the mean daily flow to achieve flow less negative than -5,000 cubic feet per second; (2) between April 1 and May 31, rates of pumping at the C.W. "Bill" Jones Pumping Plant and Harvey O. Banks Pumping Plant shall not be reduced pursuant to such NMFS opinion, except as required to implement California State Water Resources Control Board Water Rights Decision 1641 or a superseding water rights decision; and (3) between September 1 and November 30, a monthly average x2 (salinity zone index) of no greater than 74 km from the Golden Gate shall be maintained only to the extent that such action does not diminish the capability of either the Central Valley Project or the California State Water Project to make water available for other authorized project purposes. </li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior&nbsp;to&nbsp;modify such mandates&nbsp; upon recommendations of the National Research Council Committee on Sustainable Water and Environmental Management in the California Bay-Delta, if such modifications would: (1) provide greater benefits to the species covered by&nbsp;such biological opinions, and (2) not reduce the water delivery capability of such Projects more than their delivery capability allowed under such mandates.</p> <p>Requires such Secretaries to: (1)&nbsp;establish a fish hatchery program or refuge to preserve and restore the delta smelt in collaboration with the governor of California; (2)&nbsp;implement a habitat program under which each Secretary shall identify, prioritize, and implement key ecosystem restoration and fish passage projects in the ecosystem of, and on tributaries to, the California Bay-Delta to help ensure the viability of&nbsp;at-risk species and&nbsp; threatened or endangered species; and (3) install the Head of Old River Barrier during the April-May pulse flow, as set forth in California State Water Resources Control Board Water Rights Decision 1641.</p> <p>Preempts any&nbsp;state law that authorizes the imposition of restrictions on the operation of the Projects in a manner that is more restrictive than this Act.</p> <p>Terminates this Act on March 1, 2020.<br /> </p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2013-05-09</actionDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <updateDate>2013-05-09T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-06-19T17:58:02Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <updateDate>2018-06-05T16:18:23Z</updateDate>
    <committeeReports />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <notes />
    <calendarNumbers />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

