<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-02-14</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>4039</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-02-11</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S893-896)</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2016</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</latestTitle>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <latestAction>
          <actionTime>16:53:41</actionTime>
          <actionDate>2014-05-23</actionDate>
          <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <number>2198</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</latestTitle>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Huffman, Jared [D-CA-2]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>H001068</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Huffman</lastName>
        <middleName />
        <party>D</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2101</lisID>
          <bioguideId>H001068</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Jared</firstName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Appropriations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquaculture</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Atmospheric science and weather</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>California</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Justice</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Interior</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency planning and evacuation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Endangered and threatened species</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fishes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hydrology and hydrography</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Insects</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Livestock</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water quality</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water resources funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water storage</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Water use and supply</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Watersheds</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committeeReports />
    <title>To provide drought assistance to the State of California and other affected western States.</title>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <actionDate>2014-04-16</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <laws />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. HUFFMAN:H.R. 4239.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 1: The Congress shall havePower to lay and collect Taxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises,to pay the Debts and provide for the common Defence andgeneral Welfare of the United States; but all Duties, Impostsand Excises shall be uniform throughout the United States.Article I, Section 8, Clause 18: To make all Laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Office thereof.Article I, Section 9, Clause 7: No Money shall be drawnfrom the Treasury but in Consequence of Appropriations madeby Law; and a regular Statement and Account of the Receiptsand Expenditures of all public Money shall be published fromtime to time.[Page H2434]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <introducedDate>2014-03-13</introducedDate>
    <createDate>2014-03-14T07:31:23Z</createDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>FORECASTED Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Fixing Operations of Reservoirs to Encompass Climatic and Atmospheric Science Trends for Emergency Droughts Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide drought assistance to the State of California and other affected western States.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To provide drought assistance to the State of California and other affected western States.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior (Secretaries), in response to the declaration of a state of drought emergency in California, to provide the maximum quantity of water supplies possible to Central Valley Project (CVP) and Klamath Project agricultural, municipal and industrial, and refuge service and repayment contractors, State Water Project contractors, and any other locality or municipality in California. </p> <p>Sets forth actions to be taken to increase water supply, including: (1) authorizing actions to provide for real time operations of the Delta Cross Channel Gates to provide water supply and quality standards and ecosystem benefits for the duration of the drought, (2) implementing the San Joaquin River inflow-to-export ratio established by the National Marine Fisheries Service, (3) maintaining all rescheduled water supplies held in the San Luis Reservoir and Millerton Reservoir for all water users, (4) making WaterSMART grant funding administered by the Bureau of Reclamation available for eligible projects on a priority and expedited basis, and (5) issuing proposed rules to update stormwater regulations for urban and suburban runoff sources and guidance on use of rainwater capture.</p> <p>Makes emergency appropriations in FY2014 for water supply projects and assistance under the Reclamation States Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1991.</p> <p>Requires the National Resources Conservation Service to provide water supply planning assistance in preparation for and in response to dry, critically dry, and below normal water year types to any state water agency requesting such assistance. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Commerce to treat the California emergency drought declaration as a request for a determination under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act that there is a commercial fisheries failure and catastrophic regional fishery disaster for fisheries that originate in California.</p> <p>Requires federal agency heads to consult with the Council on Environmental Quality to develop alternative arrangements to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA).</p> <p>Directs the EPA Administrator to prioritize projects under state water pollution control revolving funds to provide water to areas at risk of having an inadequate supply of water for public health and safety purposes.</p> <p>Fixing Operations of Reservoirs to Encompass Climatic and Atmospheric Science Trends for Emergency Droughts Act or the FORECASTED Act - Requires the Secretary of the Army, not later than one year after a request of a non-federal sponsor of a reservoir, to review the operation of such reservoir, including the water control manual and rule curves, using improved weather forecasts and run-off forecasting methods, including the Advanced Hydrologic Prediction System of the National Weather Service and the Hydrometeorology Testbed program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to determine if a change in operations will improve core functions of the Army Corps of Engineers, including: (1) reducing risks to human life, public safety, and property; (2) reducing the need for future disaster relief; (3) improving local water storage capability and reliability in coordination with the non-federal sponsor and other water users; (4) restoring, protecting, or mitigating the impacts of a water resources development project on the environment; or (5) improving fish species habitat or population within the boundaries and downstream of a water resources project. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary, upon the declaration of a state drought emergency, to use no more than 90 days in complying with all provisions of this Act and to make use of the emergency provisions of the Council on Environmental Quality guidelines to expedite the delivery of water supplies to address emergency drought conditions. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary of Agriculture emergency supplemental appropriations to provide: (1) drought assistance to agricultural producers and for mitigation activities related to drought and wildfire hazards, (2) emergency community water assistance grants to address impacts of drought, and (3) grants to assist low-income migrant and seasonal farm workers affected by drought and for forest restoration.</p> <p>Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to determine the amount of water diverted for marijuana cultivation in each of the high intensity drug trafficking areas within the state of California, and (2) the EPA Administrator to assign additional criminal investigators to such trafficking areas.</p> <p>Declares that nothing in this Act: (1) preempts any state law, including area of origin and other water rights protections; or (2) diminishes the water, fishing, or other rights of Indian tribes or the obligations of the United States to assert and protect such rights. </p> <p>Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to expand federal emergency assistance to provide for disaster unemployment, emergency nutrition, and crisis counseling assistance.</p> <p>Amends the Klamath Basin Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to reduce water consumption or demand or to restore ecosystems in the Klamath Basin watershed, including tribal fishery resources held in trust. </p> <p>Directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, not later than January 1, 2016, in consultation with the National Marine Fisheries Service, the Bureau of Reclamation, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the California Department of Fish and Wildlife, to prepare a California salmon drought plan.</p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cost-shared financial assistance agreements with non-federal entities in Reclamation States and Hawaii for the planning, design, and construction of permanent water storage and conveyance facilities used solely to regulate and maximize water supplies..</p> <p>Directs the President to update the National Response Plan and the National Disaster Recovery Framework to include a plan for catastrophic drought.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-05-20T12:16:21Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-03-13T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>MILLER</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>11</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Miller, George [D-CA-11]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>808</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M000725</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7812</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M000725</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>GEORGE</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Garamendi</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>3</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Garamendi, John [D-CA-3]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7815</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>G000559</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1973</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>G000559</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>John</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>DEFAZIO</lastName>
        <state>OR</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>4</district>
        <fullName>Rep. DeFazio, Peter A. [D-OR-4]</fullName>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8117</gpoId>
          <lisID>279</lisID>
          <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>D000191</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>PETER</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>THOMPSON</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>5</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Thompson, Mike [D-CA-5]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1593</lisID>
          <bioguideId>T000460</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7806</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>T000460</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>MIKE</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>NAPOLITANO</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>32</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Napolitano, Grace F. [D-CA-32]</fullName>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>N000179</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1602</lisID>
          <gpoId>7843</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>N000179</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>GRACE</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>McNerney</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>9</district>
        <fullName>Rep. McNerney, Jerry [D-CA-9]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1832</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001166</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7816</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M001166</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Jerry</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Matsui</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>6</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Matsui, Doris O. [D-CA-6]</fullName>
        <middleName>O.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7810</gpoId>
          <lisID>1814</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001163</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M001163</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Doris</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>ESHOO</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>18</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Eshoo, Anna G. [D-CA-18]</fullName>
        <middleName>G.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>355</lisID>
          <gpoId>7819</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>E000215</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>E000215</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>ANNA</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>FARR</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>20</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Farr, Sam [D-CA-20]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>F000030</bioguideId>
          <lisID>368</lisID>
          <gpoId>7822</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>F000030</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>SAM</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Speier</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>14</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Speier, Jackie [D-CA-14]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1890</lisID>
          <gpoId>7817</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001175</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>S001175</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Jackie</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Bera</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>7</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Bera, Ami [D-CA-7]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2102</lisID>
          <bioguideId>B001287</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>B001287</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Ami</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Vargas</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>51</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Vargas, Juan [D-CA-51]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2112</lisID>
          <bioguideId>V000130</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>V000130</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Juan</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Lowenthal</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>47</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Lowenthal, Alan S. [D-CA-47]</fullName>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>L000579</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2111</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>L000579</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Alan</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Peters</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>52</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Peters, Scott H. [D-CA-52]</fullName>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2113</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000608</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>P000608</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Scott</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Swalwell</lastName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>15</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Swalwell, Eric [D-CA-15]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2104</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S001193</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>S001193</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Eric</firstName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <lastName>Cartwright</lastName>
        <state>PA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>17</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Cartwright, Matt [D-PA-17]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2159</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001090</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C001090</bioguideId>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Matt</firstName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-04-16</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
          <name>Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw02</systemCode>
          <name>Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
          <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-14</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif18</systemCode>
          <name>Environment and the Economy Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsbu00</systemCode>
          <name>Budget Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Budget, Agriculture, Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-03-13</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>13</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>6</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>4</placeholderTextForH>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <billNumber>4239</billNumber>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <notes />
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:11:37Z</updateDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:45Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-04-16T14:55:04Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:25Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hspw02</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-03-14T21:41:52Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Water Resources and Environment Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-03-14T21:41:35Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:40Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsif18</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-03-14T18:23:11Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <name>Environment and the Economy Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:35Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsbu00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Budget Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-03-13T14:04:20Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

