<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Connolly</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001078</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1959</lisID>
          <gpoId>8202</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <party>D</party>
        <district>11</district>
        <firstName>Gerald</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>C001078</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Connolly, Gerald E. [D-VA-11]</fullName>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. CONNOLLY:H.R. 470.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Clause 1 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution, andclause 18 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution.[Page H343]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>470</billNumber>
    <amendments />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2013-02-04T19:03:40Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Federal Executive Board Efficiency Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish Federal Executive Boards, which are defined as interagency entities established in a geographic area with a high concentration of federal employees outside the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area to strengthen the management and administration of agency activities and coordination among local federal officers to implement national initiatives in that area. Requires each Board for a geographic area to consist of a senior officer for each agency in that area.</p> <p>Requires the Director to: (1) consider specified factors in determining the location for establishment of such Boards, such as whether a geographic area has a strong, viable, and active Federal Executive Association and whether such Association petitions to become a Board; and (2) provide for the administration and oversight of such Boards, including by establishing staffing and communications policies and performance standards for Board staff.</p> <p>Requires each Board to: (1) serve as an instrument of outreach for the national headquarters of agencies relating to agency activities in the geographic area; (2) provide a forum for the exchange of information relating to programs and management methods and problems between the national headquarters of agencies and the field; (3) develop local coordinated approaches to the development and operation of programs that have common characteristics; (4) communicate management initiatives and other concerns from federal officers and employees in the Washington, D.C. area to federal officers and employees in the geographic area to achieve better mutual understanding and support; (5) develop relationships with state and local governments and nongovernmental organizations to help fulfill the roles and responsibilities of that Board; and (6) facilitate communication, collaboration, and training to prepare the federal workforce for emergencies and continuity of operations.</p> <p>Requires the Director to: (1) establish a fund within OPM for financing essential Board functions, into which contributions from the headquarters of each participating agency shall be deposited; (2) submit annual reports to Congress and agencies on Board program outcomes and budget matters; and (3) report to specified congressional committees on essential Board functions, staffing requirements, and staffing and operating expenses.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2013-02-12T15:41:50Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <updateDate>2013-02-04T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <recordedVotes />
    <notes />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Executive Board Efficiency Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To improve the efficiency of Federal Executive Boards to enhance the coordination, economy, and effectiveness of Federal agency activities, including emergency preparedness and continuity of operations, in geographic areas outside the Washington, D.C., metropolitan area.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Federal Executive Board Efficiency Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <createDate>2013-02-05T07:00:56Z</createDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <title>Federal Executive Board Efficiency Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T15:58:24Z</updateDate>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors />
    <introducedDate>2013-02-04</introducedDate>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>3</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <relatedBills />
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
      <actionDate>2013-02-04</actionDate>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Emergency planning and evacuation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Homeland security</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Office of Personnel Management (OPM)</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

