<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-07-25</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:25Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Energy and Power Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hsif03</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2014-07-25T17:44:32Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:50Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Rules Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:45Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>House Administration Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:40Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:35Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2014-07-24T14:01:20Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2014-07-25T05:01:13Z</createDate>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-07-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif03</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Power Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
          <name>Rules Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
          <name>House Administration Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
          <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
          <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
          <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Foreign Affairs, Financial Services, House Administration, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
        <links />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>7</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferralsAggregate>1</billReferralsAggregate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>11</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <introducedDate>2014-07-24</introducedDate>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>By Mr. COFFMAN:H.R. 5196.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Sec. 8, Clauses 5 & 18, of the United StatesConstitutionThese state that:``Congress shall have power to . . . coin Money, regulatethe Value thereof, and of foreign Coin, and fix the Standardof Weights and Measures.''``Congress shall have power to . . . make all Laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.''[Page H6815]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>5196</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2014-07-24</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2014-07-24T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2014-12-01T14:51:25Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>Unified Savings and Accountability Act or the USA Act - <strong>Title I: Provisions Relating to Federal Property, Federal Contracts and Information Technology</strong> - Requires: (1) the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to issue guidance to federal agencies for reinvigorating the role of the competition advocate, and (2) agency chief information officers to use transparency mechanisms to report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), annually, on efforts to identify and eliminate potentially duplicative information technology investment. </p> <p>Requires the Director of OMB to: </p> <ul> <li>issue a policy requiring consistency among all agencies in identifying information technology investments in any required reporting, </li> <li>issue government-wide savings goals for the strategic sourcing of goods and services by executive agencies required to have a Chief Financial Officer, </li> <li>require each executive agency to develop a policy consistent with OMB guidance for performing analysis to measure how well each operational/steady state information technology investment is achieving expected goals and to determine whether the investment provides the most cost effective way of delivering business value, </li> <li>issue guidance for specified agencies to complete their commodity IT baselines, </li> <li>require specified agencies to report quarterly on progress in the migration of enterprise IT systems and IT infrastructure to a shared service, and </li> <li>direct the Federal Chief Information Officer (Federal CIO) to require agencies to report on specified IT actions as part of integrated data collection quarterly reporting. </li></ul> <p>Requires: (1) the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be revised to address reverse auctions by federal agencies, and (2) the OMB Director to issue government-wide guidance advising agencies to collect and analyze data on the level of interactive bidding and fees paid to determine the cost effectiveness of using reverse auctions in procurement and on best practices to maximize competition and savings in the use of reverse auctions. </p> <p>Requires the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to develop and use criteria to prioritize potential long-term ownership solutions to current high-value leases among other capital investments and to use this ranking to create long-term cross agency strategy that facilitates consideration of targeted investments in ownership</p> <p>Requires the Federal CIO to develop, implement, and report annually on agency progress in carrying out a Federal Data Center Optimization Initiative. Requires each agency included in the Initiative to: (1) use specified </s />methods to achieve maximum server utilization and maximum energy efficiency for federal data centers, (2) use the most cost-effective measures to implement the Initiative, and (3) report to the Federal CIO annually on resulting costs and savings. Requires agency savings to be used to enhance information technology capabilities and services. </p> <p>Requires OMB to issue, and executive agencies to implement, recommendations for reducing or consolidating the number of federal data centers by at least 40% by the end of FY2018 and by at least 80% by the end of FY2023.</p> <p><strong>Title II: Other Matters</strong> - Amends the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to report on: (1) efforts to finalize plans and schedules for fully implementing and expanding the use of the Integrated Data Repository and actions taken to define expected financial benefits; and (2) actions taken to plan, schedule, and conduct training on the One Program Integrity System used to analyze and extract data from such Repository and actions taken to define expected financial benefits. </p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury, upon receiving certification by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue (IRS) that any individual has a seriously delinquent tax debt in excess of $50,000, with specified exceptions, to transmit such certification and disclose certain tax return information to the Secretary of State for action with respect to denial, revocation, or limitation of a passport for such individual pursuant to the Passport Act of 1926. Prohibits the Secretary of State, upon receiving such certification, from issuing a passport to such individual, except in emergency circumstances or for humanitarian reasons. Requires the Secretary to revoke a passport previously issued to such individual, but authorizes limiting such a passport to return travel to the United States. </p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from minting or issuing any circulating coin, or engraving or printing any U.S. currency, that costs more to produce than its denomination. </p> <p>Directs the Public Printer to make any House or Senate document available only in an electronic format that is accessible through the Internet, with specified exceptions. </p> <p>Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to: (1) sequester all $1 coins bearing the design common to those $1 coins minted and issued from 1979 through 1981 and in 1999; (2) undertake and report on efforts to improve the circulation of the $1 coin, other than those sequestered; (3) continuously conduct education programs to help businesses using or accepting cash to choose the best mix of $1 coins and bank notes to facilitate and reduce transaction costs; and (4) work with the Departments of State and Treasury to ensure that countries that have adopted the dollar as a base unit of exchange and that place orders for supplies of $1 monetary units are fully briefed on the durability and longevity of $1 coins in high-circulation economies. </p> <p>Declares it to be U.S. policy that after $1 coins achieve sufficient market penetration, $1 coins should replace $1 Federal Reserve notes. Allows Federal Reserve banks to continue to place $1 Federal Reserve notes into circulation until the number of $1 coins placed into circulation exceeds 600 million annually, or until four years after enactment of this Act, whichever is earlier. </p> <p>Directs the IRS Commissioner to develop a long-term strategy to improve web services provided to taxpayers. </p> <p>Directs the Departments of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Agriculture (USDA), and Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) analyze, annually, the effectiveness and long-term costs and benefits of their programs, actions, and strategies for avoidance or mitigation of foreclosure losses regarding loans for and mortgages on one- to four-family homes made, insured, or guaranteed by such Department; and (2) provide additional guidance on loss mitigation efforts to servicers of such loans and mortgages. </p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computers and information technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional operations and organization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Currency</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Energy efficiency and conservation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Internet and video services</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicaid</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Medicare</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Tax administration and collection, taxpayers</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Visas and passports</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <title>USA Act</title>
    <updateDate>2016-10-25T16:15:26Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>USA Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Unified Savings and Accountability Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To reduce waste and implement cost savings and revenue enhancement for the Federal Government.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>USA Act</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>CO</state>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Coffman, Mike [R-CO-6]</fullName>
        <lastName>Coffman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <middleName />
        <district>6</district>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7864</gpoId>
          <lisID>1912</lisID>
          <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1999</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>SAVE Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-05-22</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Rural Development, and Credit.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>3146</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>SAVE II Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-10-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
      <item>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>4601</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestTitle>DRIVE Now Act of 2014</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-06-03</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Rural Development, and Credit.</text>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <party>D</party>
        <firstName>Kyrsten</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Sinema</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-07-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Sinema, Kyrsten [D-AZ-9]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2099</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>S001191</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>S001191</bioguideId>
        <district>9</district>
        <state>AZ</state>
      </item>
      <item>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <party>D</party>
        <firstName>Ann</firstName>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <lastName>Kuster</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-11-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <fullName>Rep. Kuster, Ann M. [D-NH-2]</fullName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2145</lisID>
          <bioguideId>K000382</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>K000382</bioguideId>
        <district>2</district>
        <state>NH</state>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <notes />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

